absorption.
吸収。
Academia Sinica's April Intellectual Education Academy Lectures Begin
中央研究院の4月知的教育アカデミー講義が始まります
We ask Vice President Peng Xuming to host for us
彭旭明副大統領に司会をお願いします
Goodnight everybody
おやすみ皆さん
I'm glad that today is the time we miss again
今日がまた懐かしい時間になってくれて嬉しいです
The topic of today's speech
今日のスピーチのテーマ
The Big Sea of ​​Clouds The Science of Clouds and Their Role in the Global Environment
大きな雲海 雲の科学と地球環境におけるその役割
We knew this topic was very knowledgeable and interesting
このトピックが非常に知識が豊富で興味深いものであることはわかっていました
Then I think the summary of this speech is for your reference.
それでは、この講演の要旨を参考にしていただければと思います。
Especially if you read this summary after I've heard the speech
特に私がスピーチを聞いた後にこの要約を読んだ場合は
will be very helpful
とても役に立つでしょう
Then let me briefly introduce the speaker
それでは簡単に講演者を紹介させていただきます
This Dr. Huang Baoguan graduated from Tainan No. 1 Middle School in 1967
この黄宝関博士は、1967 年に台南第一中学校を卒業しました。
Then in 1971 take this break this meteorology
それから 1971 年にこの気象学を休んでください
It is now the Department of Atmospheric Sciences of National Taiwan University
現在は国立台湾大学大気科学部となっています。
Then he served in the military for two years
それから彼は2年間兵役に就いた
That was the first year of military service for two years
それは2年間の兵役の最初の年でした
I look for him for a year and I only support one year of military service
私は1年間彼を探しますが、私は1年間の兵役だけを支持します
In 1970, I fell to the United States in 1971
1970年に私はアメリカに落ちました、1971年に
I just came to this UCLA to study for a Ph.D.
私は博士号取得のために勉強するためにこの UCLA に来たところです。
Then get a doctorate in seven or eight years
それから7、8年で博士号を取得してください
in atmospheric physics
大気物理学で
Then he worked as a postdoctoral fellow and part-time assistant professor at UCLA
その後、UCLA で博士研究員および非常勤助教授として勤務しました。
From 1980 onwards in
1980 年以降、
This from the University of Wisconsin Medicine
これはウィスコンシン医科大学からのものです
This branch served as the beginning of his academic career
この支部が彼の学術的キャリアの始まりとなった
Become an associate professor in four years and a professor in four years
4年で准教授、4年で教授に就任
Professor since 1988
1988年より教授
Then from 1994 to 1997 served as the atmosphere
その後、1994 年から 1997 年まで大気として機能しました。
Dean of the Department of Marine Science
海洋科学部長
Director of the Air Resources Management Program from 1998 to 2002
1998 年から 2002 年まで大気資源管理プログラムのディレクター
The beginning of the year January 1, 2013
年の初め 2013 年 1 月 1 日
Our Central Committee is very fortunate to fight back to be our hospital
私たちの中央委員会は、私たちの病院になるために反撃することができて非常に幸運です
Director of the Center for Environmental Change
環境変動センター長
that in his academic career
それは彼の学業の中で
Been in National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学に在籍していた
Massachusetts Institute of Technology, we call MIT
マサチューセッツ工科大学、私たちはMITと呼んでいます
italy
イタリア
University of Ferrara
フェラーラ大学
University of Mex, Germany
メキシコ大学、ドイツ
besides
そのほか
German
ドイツ人
maple
麻普所
Institute of Chemistry
化学研究所
science professor or visiting professor etc.
理学部の教授や客員教授など
once obtained
一度取得したら
America's
アメリカの
Johnson's on it
ジョンソンはそれに取り組んでいる
Distinguished Scholar Award
優秀研究者賞
also received the German
ドイツ語も受けました
Homber's
ホンバーズ
this
これ
Senior Excellence Award
上級優秀賞
That
それか
used to be his main research direction
かつては彼の主な研究方向でした
is atmospheric physics
大気物理学です
especially
特に
Microphysics of clouds and rain
雲と雨の微物理
With the dynamic mechanism
ダイナミックな機構により、
Past Chair of the American Meteorological Society Committee on Cloud Physics
米国気象協会雲物理委員会の元委員長
The main and more important thing is that he has a Chinese version
一番重要でもっと重要なことは、彼が中国語版を持っているということです
cloud physics
雲の物理学
and in
そしてで
Enthusiastic about science
科学に熱中している
yes there are many
はい、たくさんあります
popular science works
ポピュラーサイエンスの作品
like heaven and earth
天と地など
from Newton Press
ニュートンプレスより
Top 10 Open Books of 1996
1996 年のオープンブック トップ 10
Then there is a book called moving tea
それから、移動茶という本があります
is the culture of the world
世界の文化です
It is the home of the first Wu Dayu Science Popularization Award
第一回呉大夫科学普及賞の開催地です。
Home of the 2002 Jinling Awards
2002 年の金陵賞の本拠地
And Wei Sung Dae-kyeom
そしてウィソンデギョム
by Classic Magazine
クラシックマガジン著
The 2005 Jinling Award finalists and so on
2005年金陵賞ファイナリストほか
So he is also very enthusiastic about this popular science.
そのため、彼はこの大衆科学にも非常に熱心です。
together we can have a good day
一緒に良い一日を過ごすことができます
this speech we all
このスピーチは私たち全員が
applaud him
彼に拍手を送ります
Thank you Vice President
副社長、ありがとう
Goodnight everybody
おやすみ皆さん
Just now the vice president did a lot
今、副大統領はたくさんのことをしました
too
太
It's an honor to introduce
ご紹介できるのは光栄です
not so honorable
それほど名誉なことではありません
but glad to have the opportunity tonight
でも今夜この機会を持てて嬉しいです
let's chat
みんなと話しに来てください
I'm doing a major in one aspect of the research I'm doing
私は行っている研究の一側面を専攻しています
I mean the speech has to have a nice name
つまり、スピーチには素敵な名前が必要です
If I talk about the science of clouds all at once
雲の科学を一気に語ると
Maybe everyone doesn't want to come
たぶんみんな来たくないと思う
But what did I say about clouds and mountains?
しかし、雲や広大な山について私は何を言ったでしょうか？
i tricked everyone
私はみんなを騙した
let's talk slowly
ゆっくり話しましょう
When the dean of our society came here for an interview,
私たちの学会の部長が面接に来たとき
At that time I didn't know whether to come or not
その時は来るか来ないか分からなかった
He told me about you this April
彼は今年の4月にあなたのことを私に話しました
He will come to us at the end of April to talk about this science in detail.
彼はこの科学について詳しく話すために4月末に私たちのところに来る予定です。
so i thought about it
それで私はそれについて考えました
I didn't know whether to come or not
来るか来ないか分からなかった
Later, I thought about it and said that I had promised others that I would come.
そこで私はよく考えて、他の人たちに来ると約束していたと言いました。
So if you don't come to this ring transformation center
だから、このリング変革センターに来ないなら
I can't seem to make sense
意味がわからないようです
I'm very happy to finish the show
番組を終えることができてとても嬉しいです
I just came here for 4 months
ここに来て4ヶ月経ちました
everything is not very very familiar
すべてがあまりよく知られていない
What I want to report to you today is
今日皆さんに報告したいことは、
something about voice
声に関する何か
common sense mostly common sense
常識 ほとんど常識
Of course it will also mention some
もちろんいくつかも言及します
We are more professional in the research part
私たちは調査部分においてより専門的です
Then my general speech is
それでは、私の一般的なスピーチは、
I don't like too much shock
あまりショックを受けるのは好きではないので
so hope
だから希望します
Needless to say we have to wait until all the speeches are over
言うまでもなく、すべてのスピーチが終わるまで待たなければなりません
only ask if you have a question
質問がある場合のみ質問してください
if you have something in the middle
真ん中に何かがある場合
small questions or relatively short
小さな質問または比較的短い質問
hope to understand soon
すぐに理解できることを願っています
I feel free to ask
お気軽に質問してください
But if you compare the question
しかし、質問を比較してみると、
Of course we'll wait until it's all over
もちろんすべてが終わるまで待ちます
But if there is such a
しかし、もしそのようなものがあれば、
small problem words
ちょっとした問題の言葉
I think you are welcome to bring it up anytime
いつでも取り上げていただいて大丈夫だと思います
OK
OK
Thanks
ありがとう
it doesn't seem to move
動かないようです
yes call me yes
はい、電話してください、はい
This has
これは持っています
yes it's ok
はい、大丈夫です
oh down ok
ああ、わかった
OK, thanks
わかりました、ありがとう
we start from that
そこから始めます
not a science start
科学の出発点ではない
so-called literature
いわゆる文学
Or generally we are right
あるいは一般的に我々は正しい
This impression of the cloud is beginning to speak well
この雲の印象がよく語り始めている
But I'm in my Zhuzhu
でも私は私のZhuzhuにいる
in that insight
その洞察の中で
People generally think that literature is not science
一般に人々は文学は科学ではないと考えています
Actually a good writer
実は良い作家さん
In fact, this kind of scientific observation has been done very carefully.
実際、この種の科学的観察は非常に注意深く行われてきました。
articles he wrote
彼が書いた記事
to reach your heart
あなたの心に届くように
that's my point of view
それが私の視点です
If everyone uses this mood in the future
この気分をこれからもみんなで使えたら
go see some litterateurs
何人かの文学者に会いに行ってください
books written by famous writers
有名な作家が書いた本
still
まだ
or article you will find
または記事が見つかります
In fact, they observed very carefully
実際、彼らは非常に注意深く観察しました
But because he observes very carefully
でも、とても注意深く観察しているので、
What he writes will move your heart
彼の書くものだけがあなたの心を動かす
so there's science in it
そこには科学が含まれています
It's not that literature means that you don't know science
文学だからといって科学を知らないわけではない
OK, what is our first impression of this cloud?
さて、この雲の第一印象は何でしょうか?
in our usual words
私たちの普段の言葉で
A lot of Guanye Yun about this choice is very elegant
この選択についてのGuanye Yunの多くは非常にエレガントです
Or it is very advantageous between some hatred
あるいは、いくつかの憎しみの間で非常に有利です
We often use language called
私たちはよく「」という言語を使います。
Flowing clouds and flowing water
流れる雲と流れる水
On behalf of others, the writing style is very good
他の人に代わって、その書き方はとても良いです
Teacher, your article is well written
先生、あなたの記事はよく書かれています
For example, like the Controversy Exhibition in our area
たとえば、私たちの地域の論争展のように
Flowing clouds and flowing water
流れる雲と流れる水
that's the right word
それは正しい言葉です
The monk who seems to have nothing at all is called Yunshui monk
何も持っていないように見える僧侶は雲水僧侶と呼ばれます
So this is also a kind of wandering everywhere
これも一種の放浪です
no homeless kind
ホームレスの類はいない
Then I just cite some examples here.
次に、ここでいくつかの例を引用します。
That's us, I think everyone probably
それが私たち、おそらく私たち全員だと思います
read these sentences
これらの文を読んでください
In the description of the cloud in these sentences
これらの文中のクラウドの説明では、
What kind of yo-yo are they all using?
彼らは皆ヨーヨーの話し方をします
Is that cloud Yoyo?
ユン・ユユさんですか？
Of course, we look at it from the eyes of ordinary people.
もちろん、私たちはそれを一般の人々の目から見ています。
indeed Yoyo
まさにヨーヨー
it just hangs there like there's nothing going on
何事もなかったかのようにそこに止まっている
Sometimes it takes a long time to hang
ハングアップに時間がかかる場合があります
Then it seems to be slightly fluttering with the wind
すると風に少しなびいてるように見えます
but i want to tell you
でも、あなたに言いたいのです
that was a wrong impression
それは間違った印象でした
Then you were deceived by the cloud
そしたら君は雲に騙された
In fact, the cloud is very busy
実際、クラウドは非常に混雑しています
Of course, that's from a scientist's point of view.
もちろん、それは科学者の観点からの話です。
I'll explain to you later
後で説明します
This shadow of Yin Yun
インユンのこの影
have this impression
この印象を持つ
A few years ago, I went to this to that Italy for a meeting
数年前、私は会議のためにイタリアへ行きました
in that so-called
いわゆるその中で
That Edrisie over there in the Adriatic Sea
あのアドリア海のエドリシ
I saw this cloud early in the morning before going to a meeting here
ここでの会議に行く前に早朝にこの雲を見ました
Come back at four or five in the afternoon
午後4時か5時に戻ってきてください
The same rain is still there
同じ雨がまだ降っている
wow that's really relaxing
うわー、本当にリラックスできます
That place seems to have just the right day and the weather is very good
あの場所はちょうど良い日のようで、天気もとても良いです
From this island, one can see that the cloud in the distance is
この島からは遠くに雲があるのが見えます。
Strange hanging all day
一日中ぶら下がっている奇妙な
So if you just look at this phenomenon, you should think that the cloud is really leisurely.
したがって、この現象だけを見れば、雲は本当にのんびりしていると考えるべきです。
It's all right hanging there like that bum sweat
あんなにお尻の汗のようにそこにぶら下がっていても大丈夫です
But what?
でも何？
When I was going to talk about it, it was also an illusion cloud. You thought he was hanging there all the time.
私がそれについて話そうとしたとき、それも幻の雲でした。彼はいつもそこにぶら下がっていると思っていました。
In fact, it's already different
実はもう違うんです
As for why it is different
なぜ違うのかというと、
you will understand later
後でわかります
But your leisure will be punished
しかしあなたの暇は罰せられるでしょう
Some people also made this cloud
この雲も作った人がいます
this one
これです
This gentleman is called Laihu
この紳士はライフと呼ばれます
that's what he's talking about
それが彼が話していることです
Thousands of Lines Looking Forward Rough Sky Hard Water Nagayama
千行望向 進荒空 硬水長山
Pian Fu Cong Unlimited Han Miao Ku Yi Bacteria
Pian Fu Cong Unlimited Han Miao Kuyi バクテリア
Yoyo, virtuous place, do prayers
よよ、善良な場所、祈りを捧げてください
He means that the cloud is in this
彼は、雲がこの中にあることを意味します
no one sees over there
あそこは誰も見てない
The place no one cares about is over there
誰も気にしない場所はそこだ
change
変化
But some of that
しかし、その一部は
Waterway, some seedlings
水路、苗木数本
fucked to death
死ぬほど犯された
he doesn't go to the rain
彼は雨の日には行かない
Still wandering over there
まだあそこをさまよっている
So this is scolding the cloud
つまりこれは雲を叱っているのです
some people don't understand
理解できない人もいます
Thought this was well done
これはよくできたと思いました
so hang him there
それで彼をそこに吊るしてください
I don't know what this is
これが何なのか分かりません
Actually a curse poem
実は呪いの詩
Cloud of Hell Round Leaf Item
地獄の雲 ラウンドリーフアイテム
That is to say, the cloud is ever-changing
つまり、クラウドは常に変化しています
We usually belong to the saying
私たちは通常、この格言に属します
Baiyuncanggou
白雲倉溝
It means that the world is actually changing
それは世界が実際に変化していることを意味します
very very big
とてもとても大きい
This source is from this
このソースはこちらから
from a poem by dufoe
デュフォーの詩より
It is "Heaven Fu Yin Fu White Clothes"
「天福陰福白衣」です。
poems and songs change like dogs
詩も歌も犬のように変化する
so the sentence
だから文は
Condensed by us into Hakuin singing dog
私たちが白隠の歌う犬を凝縮
meaning it gets very fast
つまり非常に速くなります
another one
もう一つ
The same meaning is the same as the cloud circle of the world
世界の雲の輪と同じ意味
It's just that things in the world change
世の中の状況が変わっていくだけだ
come and go
行ったり来たりする
So this world is clouded
だからこの世界は曇っている
It also means that clouds come and go
雲が行ったり来たりするという意味もあります
This is, of course, generally speaking
もちろんこれも一般論ですが
Observed cloud changes are very fast
観測された雲の変化は非常に速い
Usually if you like to watch the cloud
通常、雲を見るのが好きなら
I myself have loved watching clouds since I was a child.
私は子供の頃から雲を見るのが大好きでした。
So study the cloud
だからクラウドを勉強してください
probably not wrong
おそらく間違ってはいない
Many of you here may like to watch clouds
雲を見るのが好きな方も多いのではないでしょうか
i have one thing to say
一つ言いたいことがある
please don't look while driving
運転中は見ないでください
very dangerous
すごく危ない
because it's fascinating
それは魅力的だから
Suddenly found this problem out
突然この問題に気づきました
But one of the clouds is very special
でも雲の中の一つはとても特別です
That is to say, when you look at you, it is equal to
つまり、あなたを見たとき、それは次のことに等しいです。
You just blink and it has become the same
まばたきするだけで同じになってしまった
Do you feel like a fish is growing
魚が成長しているような気がしますか？
then you might say take a break
それなら休みなさいって言うかもしれない
Or someone just called you
あるいは、誰かがあなたに電話をかけてきました
You spread it out for another 20 seconds
さらに20秒間広げます
That fish might disappear
あの魚は消えるかもしれない
very strange
非常に奇妙な
So some people have been dreaming
それで夢を見ている人もいる
that is to say the fish
つまり魚です
How on earth is it possible to become so fast
いったいどうしたらそんなに速くなれるのか
Then there is a
それから、
there is a video
ビデオがあります
A small movie can be
小さな映画であれば、
You can see how the fish is changing
魚の変化がわかります
oh
おお
can't come back
戻れない
this is going to be moved above this
これはこの上に移動されます
You can see the fish have formed
魚が形成されているのがわかります
maybe i see this
これを見てください
This is like a dog
これは犬みたいですね
like a cat or something
猫か何かのように
this is changing
これは変わりつつある
sometimes it seems like something out of nothing
時には何もないところから何かが生まれたように見えることもある
Sometimes it pops up out of nowhere
時々それはどこからともなく現れる
So this of course speeds up the time
もちろんこれにより時間は短縮されます
This is a kind of time lapse to tell the truth
真実を言うと、これは一種のタイムラプスです
honestly this movie
正直この映画
But I have to say so you can see
でも、見てわかるように言わなければなりません
It is said that the change of the cloud is indeed very fast.
確かに雲の変化は早いと言われます。
and it turns into this
そしてそれはこうなります
suddenly become like that
突然そうなる
so this is
それでこれは
Why does it cause the so-called world cloud change
なぜそれがいわゆる世界の雲の変化を引き起こすのか
such an impression
そんな印象
Then you see this cloud now
そうしたら今この雲が見えます
Of course, it's mainly chicken clouds on sunny days
もちろん晴れた日は鶏雲がメインです
that under different weather conditions
さまざまな気象条件下で
Variations of various clouds
さまざまな雲のバリエーション
Another way
別の方法
OK
OK
So not just the kind of cloud itself
つまり、クラウドそのものの種類だけではなく、
dynamic changes
動的変化
Even clouds come in all shapes and sizes
雲にもさまざまな形や大きさがあります
are various changes
さまざまな変化があります
like this cloud
この雲のように
Everyone must have seen it
誰もが見たことがあるはずです
This kind of cloud is called cirrus cloud
このような雲はいわゆる巻雲です
It's probably very, very long
おそらくとてもとても長いです
so often this slightly acts like a hook
多くの場合、これはわずかにフックのように機能します
Westerners say this is like a horse's tail
西洋人はこれを馬の尻尾に似ていると言います
that ponytail cloud
あのポニーテールの雲
that's true
それは本当だ
It's usually shaped like this
だいたいこんな形です
very long very
非常長非常
Often the entire sky is filled with a mass of these clouds
多くの場合、空全体がこれらの雲の塊で満たされます
That used to be in basic meteorology
それは基礎的な気象学で使用されていました
Teachers often say that you see this kind of cloud
先生はよく「こんな雲があるね」と言います。
it means the weather may change
天気が変わるかもしれないという意味です
But sometimes I watched for a long time
でも、長い間見ていたこともありました
The weather may not change
天気は変わらないかもしれない
Weather, if you only look at clouds
天気、雲だけ見ると
This is not very accurate
これはあまり正確ではありません
That thing has changed a lot
その点は少し変わりました
But what about this cirrus cloud?
しかし、この巻雲はどうでしょうか？
Cirrus clouds are actually high-altitude clouds
巻雲は実際には高層の雲です
it's very high
とても高いです
usually very thin
通常也非常薄
What I mean by thin is thin
薄いというのは薄いという意味です
But it's not thin in terms of thickness
でも厚み的には薄くない
its possible after a few kilometers
数キロ後には可能です
I generally think that
一般的にはそう思います
This seems to be within a few hundred meters.
ここは数百メートル以内のようです。
Actually no
実は違う
cirrus clouds may be several kilometers away
巻雲は数キロ離れている可能性があります
but it's thin
でも薄いです
so you can see right through it from the ground
地上からでもよく見えるので
so it looks like
だからそれはのように見える
when the sun shines
太陽が輝くとき
it's very very bright
とてもとても明るいです
Because it's mostly ice crystals
ほとんどが氷の結晶だから
so this kind of thing
それでこのようなこと
cirrus
巻雲
This is more familiar to everyone
こちらの方が誰にとっても馴染み深いものです
Of course there are small and big cirrus clouds
もちろん大小の巻雲もある
that movie we just had
たった今観たあの映画
That is called sunny cirrus
それは晴れ巻雲と呼ばれます
because it was sunny
晴れていたので
cirrus clouds
巻雲
this one is bigger
こっちの方が大きいです
This is from that accountant
これはあの会計士からです
founding out
創業する
This is what we call dense cirrus cloud
これは私たちが濃い巻雲と呼ぶものです
because it grows a bit bigger
もう少し大きくなるので
Then you can see the shape
そうすると形が見えてきます
I think of when you eat
食べるときのことを考える
The kind that eats that cauliflower
あのカリフラワーを食べる種類
You see cauliflower, this is gene
カリフラワーを見てください、これは遺伝子です
If you like Niu-Stopology and you see this thing, this one is convection
Niu-Stopology が好きでこれを見たら、これは対流です
Why convection? There is this relative movement between the air outside and the air inside
なぜ対流が起こるのでしょうか? 外側の空気と内側の空気の間には相対的な動きがあります。
So there are a lot here, if you look at them carefully, it looks like a small team bag
ここにはたくさんあるので、よく見ると小さなチームバッグのように見えます
keep moving
動き続ける
I saw it when I was a kid, I practiced this reservoir very early
子供の頃に見た、とても早い時期にこの貯水池を練習した
This is Yun Zhongjun from Chuchi Nine Brothers
Chuchi Nine BrothersのYun Zhongjunです
This is one of the ancient cloud gods
これは古代の雲神の一人です
In his commentary, I just wanted to laugh when I saw it, Yun Zhongjun is Yunshen Fenglong
彼のコメントでは、読んでいると笑いたくなります、ユン・ジョンジュンはユンシェン・フォンロンです
I believe that name is all about being there
その名前は完全にそこにあるべきものだと信じています
You see this kind of gene, it really looks fat
この種の遺伝子を見ると、本当に太って見えます
Of course it's very windy
もちろん風がとても強いです
He said another name is Ping Yi
別の名前はピンイーだと言った
This simplicity simply means to block things.
この単純さは単に物事をブロックすることを意味します。
Of course, the cloud is blocking the sun
もちろん、太陽を遮る雲はさらに多くなります
So this god's name is probably a bit artificial.
したがって、この神の名前はおそらく少し人工的です。
This kind of cloud you often see this so-called achievement
よく見かけるこの種のクラウド、いわゆる実績
You say like it's not full of the sky
空がいっぱいじゃないみたいに君は言う
But you can divide it piece by piece
でも、部分ごとに分割することもできます
So this kind of cloud is also full
なのでこんな雲もいっぱいです
The other one is called a convective cloud
もう一つは対流雲と呼ばれるものです
Convective clouds are
対流雲は、
Usually its vertical scale is a bit larger than its horizontal scale
通常、垂直スケールは水平スケールよりも少し大きくなります。
So this is generally produced by convection
したがって、これは一般に対流によって生成されます
Then this is of course the cloudy weather in summer in Taiwan.
それから、これはもちろん台湾の夏の曇り空です。
And this kind of cloud you usually see
そして、あなたがよく見るこの種の雲
More likely means that there is a chance of rain often
可能性が高いということは、頻繁に雨が降る可能性があることを意味します
Also this kind of cloud, since it is so thick, it means
また、このような雲は、厚いので、
Some of his ascenders are very strong
彼のアセンダーのいくつかは非常に強力です
Some ascenders are so strong
一部のアセンダーは非常に強力です
There is a high chance of rain
雨が降る可能性が高いです
But it's also a possibility
でも可能性もあるよ
If you say he will definitely rain
君が言ったら絶対に雨が降るよ
Not always
常にではない
sometimes he can't get down
時々彼は降りられない
But the so-called not coming down means not getting down to the ground
でも、いわゆる降りていないというのは、地面に降りていないということです。
if you are in the rain
雨の中にいるなら
then he will come down
そうすれば彼は降りてくるだろう
If you go back into the rain
また雨の中へ行ったら
There are many raindrops on that window
その窓にはたくさんの雨粒が落ちています
On that glass of this plane
この飛行機のあのガラスの上で
you can see
見ることができます
There must be strong raindrops in this convective rain
この対流雨の中には強い雨粒が降っているに違いない
when a convective rain
対流性の雨が降ったとき
Like when I grew up in a tall place just now
さっきまで高い所で育った頃のように
This usually reaches a certain height
通常、これは一定の高さに達します
That height we call convective sinking
私たちが対流沈下と呼ぶその高さ
The lowest layer of the atmosphere on the ground
地上の大気の最下層
We call it convective sinking
それを対流沈下と呼びます
Basically, he arrived at about 10 kilometers.
基本的には10キロくらいで到着しました。
sometimes ten kilometers
時には10キロメートル
onto that
その上に
another city
別の都市
There is probably Stratocity over ten kilometers away.
おそらく10キロ以上離れたところにストラトシティがあるでしょう。
Stratocity-like movement is difficult to penetrate
ストラトシティ的な動きは浸透しにくい
So the general cloud goes to this convective city
それで、一般的な雲はこの対流都市に行きます
It's like there's an invisible glass blocking it
まるで目に見えないガラスがそれを遮っているようだ
your convection basin to the top
対流盆地を頂上まで引き上げる
its cloud won't go up
その雲は上がらない
But it can always be opened from the side
でも横からはいつでも開けられます
So it has this kind of opening on both sides
両側にこのような穴が開いています
So this so-called chicken cloud
つまり、このいわゆるチキンクラウド
Chicken clouds are generally connected with the so-called lightning phenomenon
鶏雲は一般に、いわゆる雷現象と関連しています。
Usually it produces lightning and thunder
通常は稲妻や雷鳴が発生します
this phenomenon
この現象
This is the so-called chicken cloud
いわゆるチキンクラウドです
Just now, it was probably the general impression we have of clouds.
先ほど、私たちが雲に対して抱いている一般的な印象はこれだったかもしれません。
what is it like
それはどんな感じですか
Let me see what the artist thinks about this cloud
アーティストがこの雲についてどう思っているか見てみましょう
this belt this
このベルトはこれ
A painter named Guo Xi
郭熙という画家
Everyone, if you go to the Boyuan of the Forbidden City
皆さん、紫禁城の博園に行くなら
There are several very large paintings
とても大きな絵がいくつかあります
He once wrote an article called "Linquan Gaozhi"
彼はかつて「林泉高志」という記事を書いた。
He narrates a lot in it
彼はその中で多くのことを語ります
If you want to draw clouds, how should you draw them?
雲を描きたい場合、どうやって描けばいいのでしょうか？
Of course he mainly said
もちろん彼は主にこう言いました
The clouds in spring should be like white cranes
春の雲は白鶴のようであってほしい
The wind is blowing
風が吹いている
This makes sense
意味あり
Because the convection is stronger in summer
夏は対流が激しいので
Just like the convection just now
ちょうど今の対流のように
so summer clouds
だから夏の雲
A lot of them are like this kind of strange mountain.
こういう不思議な山のようなものが多いです。
autumn and winter clouds
秋と冬の雲
Each has its own characteristics
それぞれに独自の特徴があります
that this
これは
Later this
この後
It may be the ring garden in the Ming Dynasty
明代の環状庭園かもしれない
In the picture book, it is a great article about the cloud coming to heaven and earth
絵本では雲が天地にやってくる素晴らしい記事です
Qianyan of Mountains and Rivers is too busy in the future
山と川の銭燕は今後も忙しすぎる
You have to draw some clouds when you draw too much this Qianyan
このQianyanを描きすぎると、雲をいくつか描く必要があります
make him look slanted
彼を斜めに見せる
After that request, I am too willing to do so
そのリクエストの後は、私も喜んでそうするつもりです
What are you going to do because there are so few things?
物が少ないからどうする？
You also draw some shadows, he looks a little busy
影も描いて、ちょっと忙しそう
So this has this wonderful effect
これには素晴らしい効果があります
I think what he said is quite reasonable.
彼の言ったことは非常に合理的だと思います。
I found two examples, the first one is
2 つの例を見つけました。最初の例は次のとおりです。
These two are from the Yuan Dynasty. Wang Meng has one called
この二人は元の時代のもので、王蒙には と呼ばれる者がいます。
Juquling Wutu, what about this pot?
ジュクリン・ウトゥ、この鍋はどうですか？
Wang Meng is of course a Taoist of the Yuan Dynasty
王蒙はもちろん元代の道士です。
So of course his brush is very good
もちろん彼のブラシはとても良いです
But I think this earth dragon is too urgent
でもこの地竜は急ぎすぎると思う
It's like I can't breathe
息ができないみたいだ
The densely packed trees he drew are also stones
彼の描いた密集した木々も石です
If he can draw a little cloud in the middle
真ん中に小さな雲を描くことができたら
Looks like it's more likely not to be in such a hurry
そんなに急ぐ必要はなさそうです
The other easel is better for him
他のイーゼルの方が彼には良い
He has a lot of mountains and fields, but there are some clouds in the middle of him.
彼にはたくさんの山と野原がありますが、彼の真ん中にはいくつかの雲があります。
Of course, the so-called cloud is actually the same as there is no painting
もちろん、いわゆる雲は絵が描かれていないのと同じです
mostly blank
ほとんど空白
So it seems less urgent
なので緊急性は低いようです
he doesn't feel like he can't breathe
彼は息ができないとは感じていない
So the cloud does have this magical effect
雲には魔法のような効果があるのですね
Like this is Dong Qicha from the Ming Dynasty, Shu Hua's family
これは明代の董其茶、朱華の家族です
He's not really that professional a painter
彼はそれほどプロの画家ではない
Three strokes and two strokes of literati paintings by him
彼の文人画三画二画
So he didn't have much time to draw in such detail
そのため、彼にはそのような詳細を描く時間があまりありませんでした
So he used the awareness just now
それで彼は今その意識を使いました
He said that you, Zhuo Yi, are too suspicious of a male Yun Mangzi
彼は、あなた、Zhuo Yi は男性の Yun Mangzi を疑いすぎていると言った。
You just use that cloud to make it look like there's something in it
その雲を使って、中に何かがあるように見せるだけです
So what he actually painted is the black place.
つまり、彼が実際に描いたのは黒い場所です。
this place is left blank
この場所は空白のままです
But you seem to say it's a cloud
でも君はそれを雲だと言っているようだ
I would imagine that there might be trees behind that cloud
あの雲の後ろに木があるかもしれないと想像します
Actually he didn't say that
実際には彼はそんなことは言っていませんでした
But that's what's in your head
でもそれが君の頭の中にあるんだ
There must be something behind that cloud
あの雲の向こうには何かがあるに違いない
So this is the so-called Zhuo Yi too disliked
つまり、これはいわゆるZhuo Yiがあまりにも嫌いです
Male Yun Manzi makes him look a little more manly
男性のユン・マンジは彼をもう少し男らしく見せます
this is not bad
これは悪くない
Therefore, Chinese painters
したがって、中国の画家たちは、
There are many theories of phonetics
音声学には多くの理論があります
But the modern voice
でも現代の声は
That is to say, the voice painting in this Chinese painting is the best
つまりこの中国画の声絵が最高なんです
It may be the late Mr. Huang Junbi
故ファン・ジュンビさんかもしれない
His nickname is Master of Baiyun Hall
彼のニックネームは白雲堂のマスターです。
So I think he's already very, very confident with this voice painting
だから彼はすでにこのボイスペインティングに非常に自信を持っていると思います
That's true, his voice and painting are quite good.
確かに声も絵もとても良いです。
He painted voices better than those painters of previous generations
彼は前の世代の画家よりも上手に声を描いた
He draws more realistically
彼はもっとリアルに描いています
So this one is one of his rhythms
つまり、これは彼のリズムの 1 つです
He often mentions a
彼はよく次のことについて言及します
Looking at the green mountains and deep white clouds are all the feelings of hometown
緑の丘、深く白い雲、白い雲を眺めると故郷を感じる
also very realistic
とても現実的でもあります
But I have one dissatisfaction with our Chinese painter
しかし、中国の画家には一つ不満があります。
Dissatisfaction is that
不満というのは、
Half the day they drew his clouds looked the same
彼らが描いた半日の雲は同じように見えた
He didn't try to draw other clouds
彼は他の雲を描こうとはしなかった
He also didn't try to draw cloud shadows
彼は雲の影も描こうとしなかった
Its camp is basically next to the mountain
そのキャンプは基本的に山の隣にあります
Then there are some clouds
その後、少し雲が出てきました
So after talking for half a day
それで半日話し合った結果、
The main purpose of its cloud painting is to set off the mountains
雲の絵の主な目的は山々を際立たせることです。
That's all
それで全部です
So although it has a lot of theory about painting clouds
雲の描画については多くの理論がありますが、
it doesn't really execute
実際には実行されません
How should the cloud be drawn, how to draw, how to draw
雲をどう描くか、どう描くか、どう描くか。
So at least I read a lot about the Forbidden City.
だから少なくとも私は紫禁城についてはよく読みました。
It seems that I haven't really found a serious one.
どうやら深刻なものは見つかっていないようです。
Example of drawing that different cloud
別の雲の描画例
But speaking of Western paintings
しかし西洋絵画といえば
It's almost like that in ancient times
古代でもほぼそうなんです
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
When we draw clouds, we draw a cloud
雲を描くときは雲を描きます
And the cloud in the ancient western paintings is not the main character
そして古代西洋絵画の雲は主役ではない
Ancient paintings are all figures
古代の絵画はすべて人物像である
so be the protagonist
だから主人公になってください
Then draw a cloud in that least heavy corner
次に、最も重くない隅に雲を描きます
It seems like a place full of clouds
雲だらけの場所のようです
This probably lasted until the Impressionist came out.
これはおそらく印象派が登場するまで続いたでしょう。
I really started to pay attention to that cloud
私はその雲に本当に注目し始めました
Draw that cloud very realistically
その雲をとてもリアルに描きます
And not only the clouds are very realistic
雲が非常にリアルであるだけではありません
That kind of scene turns into clouds and shines on each other
そんな景色が雲となって照らし合う
Various coordination between online
オンラインとの様々な連携
very well drawn
とてもよく描かれています
This is the master of impressionism
これが印象派の巨匠です
his master
彼の主人
This one is called Caude Monet
これはコード・モネと呼ばれるものです
painted
描きました
He speaks from the point of view of this cloudy school
彼はこの曇り空の学校の視点から語る
he drew it exactly right
彼はそれを正確に描いた
Exactly like Convection Shadow
まさに対流影と同じ
Ba Xiao
バ・シャオ
And where should his shadow be?
そして彼の影はどこにあるべきでしょうか？
Then the bottom should look like
すると、底部は次のようになります。
I have nothing to say
何も言うことはない
that's him
それは彼です
Indeed, the painting is very, very
確かに、絵はとてもとても素晴らしいです
lifelike
生き生きとした
just that part
その部分だけ
I think
私が思うに
although i can't draw
私は絵が描けないのに
but i think
しかし、私は思います
if you study hard
一生懸命勉強すれば
very well said
非常によく言いました
But after I saw this
でもこれを見た後は
I said that there is nothing I can do about it
それについては何もできないと言いました
I don't think I can draw this
これは描けないと思う
my first time in
私の初めての
I'm in Paris, France
私はフランスのパリにいます
that
それか
I was actually at a place called Caude Pong
実は私はCaude Pongという場所にいました
that that that that
それはそれはそれは
when i saw this picture
この写真を見たとき
just thought about it
ちょうどそれについて考えた
Somebody come in and really can draw
誰か来て本当に絵を描ける人
get this cloud out
この雲を取り除いてください
One of the reasons is that
理由の 1 つは、
The first one I am very sensitive to this cloud
1つ目は、この雲に非常に敏感です
Every time the sky derails this cloud
空がこの雲を狂わせるたびに
My whole body is uncomfortable
体全体が不快です
I just said I've been thinking about it for a long time and I can't figure it out
ずっと考えてるんだけど分からないって言ったんだ
Later I figured out why
後でその理由が分かりました
so i'll explain later
だから後で説明するよ
But I've ever felt that way
でもそう感じたことはある
That is, if anyone can take the cloud
つまり、誰かがクラウドを利用できるとしたら
That kind of cloud can be drawn with that brush
あのブラシならあんな雲も描ける
I admire it very much
とても感心します
I ended up visiting this museum.
結局この美術館を訪れることになりました。
There is such a painting in this demon
この悪魔にはこんな絵がある
This means it's not sunny
つまり晴れていないということです
but it's not raining
でも雨は降っていない
It's half sunny and half rainy
半分晴れ、半分雨です
at a glance
一目でわかる
When I saw it, I felt that the cloud was really uncomfortable.
それを見て、雲が本当に気持ち悪いと感じました。
That's an amazing art too
それも素晴らしい芸術ですね
So this is very, very powerful
これは非常に強力です
I don't see anyone else drawing
他に描いている人がいない
draw it like this
このように描いてください
that mentioned why
それは理由を述べた
Just look at this picture first
まずはこの写真を見てください
This one is the so-called high-speed luck
こちらはいわゆる高速運です
You may often see this
これはよく見るかも知れません
What impression do you usually have when you see this kind of luck?
このような幸運を見たとき、あなたは普段どのような印象を持ちますか？
what kind of weather do you usually live in
あなたは普段どんな天気で住んでいますか
See what Gao Jiyun looks like
ガオ・ジユンがどのようなものかを見てください
like a fish spirit
魚の精のような
Does anyone care to guess
誰か推測したい人はいますか
Or tell me about your usual impression
もしくは普段の印象を教えてください
actually not
実際にはそうではありません
This kind of luck is good when the weather is good
天気が良いとこういう運気も良いですね
Yulingtian
玉陵田
This kind of high-speed luck is usually when the sky is better
この種の高速運は通常、空が良いときに起こります
and the background can often be seen through
背景が透けて見えることもよくあります
see above that blue sky
あの青い空の上を見てください
This is actually mentioned in many elementary and middle school textbooks
実はこのことは、多くの小中学校の教科書に載っています。
But when he mentioned it he often said
しかし、それについて話すとき、彼はよくこう言いました。
If you see this cloud like fish spirit
魚の精のようなこの雲を見たら
yes means sunny
はいは晴れを意味します
I think this sentence is a bit redundant
この文は少し冗長だと思います
This sentence is of course true
この文はもちろん真実です
So this is of little significance, it should be like this, that is to say, if you see this kind of cloud, and then it becomes a piece, and becomes a whole cloud, it means that the weather is going to be bad
つまり、これはあまり意味がありません、こうあるべきです、つまり、この種の雲が見えて、それが部分になって、全体の雲になったら、それは天気が悪くなることを意味します
Why? Because when you have this kind of cloud, it usually represents small-scale convection, one by one small convection packets, and it is not very deep, it is a small and shallow convection, so it is not itself not thick
なぜかというと、この種の雲があるとき、それは通常、小規模な対流を表し、1つずつ小さな対流パケットを表し、それほど深くはなく、小さくて浅い対流なので、それ自体は厚くないからです。
But if they are connected together, it means that there is a large-scale movement approaching, so the whole air will rise upwards
しかし、それがつながっている場合は、大規模な動きが近づいていることを意味するため、空気全体が上に上昇します
When you see this convection, some of the air rises and some of it goes down, but when you see the whole becomes one piece, then the weather starts to get bad
この対流を見ると、空気の一部が上昇し、一部が下降しますが、全体が一つになると、天気が悪化します。
If it's the other way around, you first see a large layer of cloud formation, and then come on, it suddenly becomes this
逆の場合は、最初に大きな層の雲が形成され、その後戻ってきて、突然このようになります。
the weather will get better
天気は良くなるでしょう
This situation means that when I was a freshman or sophomore
この状況は、私が1年生か2年生のときに
I just learned a little bit about this
これについて少しだけわかったのですが
very happy
とても幸せです
I just got married
結婚したばかりです
it rained heavily that morning
その朝は大雨が降りました
Of course everyone is very troubled
もちろんみんな困ってるよ
It's finally raining
ついに雨が降ってきました
It's inconvenient to get married when it rains
雨が降ると結婚するのは不便だ
Trouble with guests
ゲストとのトラブル
Sometimes I told him that I hadn't studied the heptathlon
時々、私は七種競技を勉強したことがないと彼に言います。
Soon about ten o'clock
もうすぐ10時くらい
I saw that the blue sky began to have a few pieces of this small
青空がこの小さな破片をいくつか持ち始めているのが見えました
This kind of high-speed machine looks like it came out
こんな高速マシンが出てきたみたいです
I'm bold enough to tell my father
私は勇気を出して父に言います
Don't worry, the weather will improve
心配しないでください、天気は良くなります
Sure enough, more than an hour
案の定、1時間以上
Slowly and slowly the whole cost becomes the whole rain
ゆっくりゆっくり、すべてのコストがすべての雨になる
slowly become like this
徐々にこうなる
rain like rain
雨のような雨
In the afternoon, it was simply the situation.
午後になると、まさにそのような状況になりました。
So I'm very impressed with doing
だからとても感動しました
It's a good day to see high altitude clouds
高層雲を見るには良い日です
Everyone knows about this painting
この絵については誰もが知っています
The problem is that you want to change the shape of the cloud from this
問題は、ここから雲の形を変更したいことです。
go see what the weather will be like
天気がどうなるか見に行ってください
which is more important
どちらがより重要ですか
so you want to understand this
だからあなたはこれを理解したいのですか
Of course you need to understand
もちろん理解する必要があります
Where did this cloud come from?
この雲はどこから来たのでしょうか?
so after knowing this
だからこれを知った上で
It's more interesting to look at the cloud
雲を見るともっと面白い
Some western flower family even even clouds
西洋の花の仲間、雲さえも
Those were a little more static
それらはもう少し静的でした
The painting is a little dynamic
絵は少しダイナミックです
because it draws clouds
雲を描くから
This is clearly a dense cloud
これは明らかに濃い雲です
and it's beyond the clouds
そしてそれは雲の向こうにある
look at the windy direction
風が吹く方向を見てください
sometimes see that cloud
時々あの雲が見える
especially in autumn
特に秋に
The higher wind is stronger
上空ほど風が強い
It can blow clouds from side to side
雲を左右に吹き飛ばすことができる
you can see this cloud
この雲が見えます
so-called wind shear
いわゆるウインドシア
so it's obvious
それは明らかです
The wind on this upper level blows from the right to the left
この上層部の風は右から左に吹く
This is an American painter's Junker
これはアメリカ人画家のユンカーです
He just made it so that he wasn't really one of us.
彼は自分が本当は私たちの一員ではないように仕向けただけなのです。
But the scenery he painted
でも彼が描いた景色は
It’s just the scenery near the Metis where I live
私の住んでいるメティスの近くの風景です
exactly like this
まさにこのように
some countryside then some trees
いくつかの田園地帯、そしていくつかの木々
And did you see that autumn really is
そして本当に秋が来たのを見ましたか？
This very high cloud then goes in a certain direction
この非常に高い雲は特定の方向に進みます
I just asked my students
生徒たちに聞いてみたところ
After you see this painting, is there any way to warm it up on the ground?
この絵を見た後、地面で暖める方法はありますか？
As the altitude changes then the wind on the ground follows the wind direction at altitude
高度が変化すると、地上の風は高度での風向きに従います。
We call the explorer refusal, is there a way to write it out?
探索者を拒否と呼んでいますが、それを書き出す方法はありますか?
It should be possible
それは可能なはずです
If you are familiar with the terroir of a place
場所のテロワールに詳しい場合
In addition to these individual clouds just now
今のこの個々の雲に加えて
I have all kinds of scenery
いろんな景色があるよ
Like our sea of ​​clouds, a friend of mine named Zhuang Kaihua took this picture
私たちの雲海のように、Zhuang Kaihuaという名前の私の友人がこの写真を撮りました
This one is in Miaoli
これは苗栗にあります
Miaoli seems to be called crow leaf or something
苗栗はカラスの葉か何かと呼ばれているようです
where we are over there
私たちがそこにいる場所
we go camping over there
私たちはあそこでキャンプに行きます
We often see this in Taiwan
台湾ではよく見かけます
The whole cloud submerges the mountain like the sea
雲全体が海のように山を沈める
So it's a cloud phenomenon
つまり、それは雲現象です
often in the valley
谷でよくある
early in the morning
早朝に
maybe the weather is nice
天気がいいかもしれない
But slowly the wind blows
でもゆっくりと風が吹いて
you can see the whole valley
谷全体が見えます
empty full of clouds
雲がいっぱいで空っぽ
a piece exactly like the sea
まさに海のような一枚
So this sea of ​​clouds is really like a sea of ​​clouds
なのでこの雲海は本当に雲海のようです
Yunshan is really a mountain
雲山は本当に山です
This is the plane I took
これは私が乗った飛行機です
Already flew at a peak of about 12,000 meters
すでに高度約12,000メートルの頂上を飛行
But because of the clouds above
でも、上空には雲があるので、
taller than this plane
この飛行機よりも高い
Twelve thousand meters
12,000メートル
world's highest peak
世界最高峰
Come to Mount Everest this time
今度はエベレストに来てください
Or I will code the wind in mainland China
さもなければ中国本土の風をコード化するだろう
Only more than 8000 less than 9000 meters
8000メートル以上9000メートル未満のみ
So if you move Inoki male king to
つまり、猪木男性キングを
same place
同じ場所
still below
まだ下にあります
Clouds in our Taiwan summer
台湾の夏の雲
It's just ten kilometers
たった10キロです
The kind of summer that makes cloud-based tops
雲の上のトップスを作るような夏
About 12 to 13 kilometers
約12～13キロ
At least
少なくとも
When it is more vigorous, sometimes 15
もっと活発なときは、15 になることもあります
15 6 km
15 6km
are very high clouds
とても高い雲です
Your so-called highest peak in the world is actually still
あなたのいわゆる世界最高峰は、実はまだ残っています。
still much lower than that
まだそれよりもはるかに低い
Simply
単に
89 kilometers like this
こんな感じで89キロ
This is also based on
これもベースにしています
This is all you can see if you look at him from a plane based on
をベースにした飛行機から彼を見ると、これだけが見えます。
Basically, it grows long and long from a very low place a few hundred meters
基本的には数百メートルの非常に低い場所から長く伸びます。
grow to
に成長する
ten kilometers high
高さ10キロメートル
So if you haven't been to this Everest
もしあなたがこのエベレストに行ったことがないなら
if moved in front of your eyes
目の前で動いたら
how high will it be
どれくらい高くなりますか
It's not really that high
実はそんなに高くないんです
So this can give you a better reference point is
これにより、より良い参照点が得られます。
Of course not all clouds are happy
もちろん、すべての雲が幸せなわけではありません
Some clouds look a little scary
雲が少し怖く見えます
This is called a milky advanced cloud
これをミルキーアドバンスクラウドといいます
This is usually in this kind of cloud with this storm
この嵐ではいつもこのような雲の中です
very relevant cloud
非常に関連性の高いクラウド
You can see it this below
以下で見ることができます
Round and round, a bit like that cow
ぐるぐる、あの牛にちょっと似てる
Saggy bunch of this cow's milk like
この垂れ下がった牛乳の束のようなもの
So we call it milky high cloud
だから私たちはそれをミルキーハイクラウドと呼びます
I remember Li He in the Tang Dynasty
唐の時代の李和を思い出します
Also wrote a poem called Black Cloud
「黒い雲」という詩も書いた
Duck City Chen Yuchui
アヒルシティ チェン ユーチュイ
The false light is like golden clouds blooming on the sun
假光像日金雲開
he wrote this scene
彼はこのシーンを書きました
I think it's exactly like the scene I took that time
あの時撮った風景と全く同じだと思う
This is the so-called milky advanced cloud
これがいわゆるミルキーアドバンスクラウドです
how did this come about
これはどうやって起こったのですか
now everyone is arguing
今、みんなが議論しています
have different theories
さまざまな理論がある
But why would he cause
しかし、なぜ彼は原因を引き起こすのでしょうか
It just so happens that this kind of spherical shape is very strange.
たまたまですが、このような球形は非常に奇妙です。
Gao Jin's advocacy just now also looks strange.
高進氏の今の主張も奇妙に見える。
But it's not scary
でも怖くないよ
This movie is more scary
この映画はもっと怖いです
This shadow is what we call the strong shadow
この影を私たちは強い影と呼んでいます
Walk on
歩いて行こう
basically you can see this ground
基本的にこの地面が見えます
This shadow is like a big one of this kind
この影はこの種の大きな影のようです
Vacuum cleaner blows down from the sky again
また掃除機が空から落ちてくる
If you just stood below
ただ下に立っていれば
The hot water is sucked up
お湯が吸い取られる
It's like an alien machine
まるで宇宙人の機械のようだ
Of course you see this cloud
もちろんこの雲が見えます
i think you better run faster
もっと早く走った方がいいと思います
Because this kind of shadow is the precursor of a tornado
こういう影は竜巻の前兆だから
This cloud usually appears
この雲は通常現れる
Signs of a tornado
竜巻の兆候
This wall-like circle of clouds
この壁のような雲の輪
Then it's slowly turning
それからゆっくりと回転します
That tornado doesn't seem to appear slowly
その竜巻はゆっくりと現れないようだ
some slowly
ゆっくりと
but there are
しかし、あります
when you look happy like this
こうやって幸せそうに見えると
it came suddenly
それは突然やって来た
Maybe it's right in front of your eyes
もしかしたらそれはあなたの目の前にあるかもしれません
Suddenly a tornado appeared
突然竜巻が現れた
it will be like this
このようになります
So when you see this cloud phenomenon
ですから、この雲の現象を見ると、
This is to find a place to hide
これは隠れる場所を見つけるためです
or lower your voice
または声を低くしてください
Maybe it's safer
もしかしたらその方が安全かもしれない
Those just now are not very scientific
今の話はあまり科学的ではありません
those are a chat
それらはチャットです
let's take a look now
今見てみましょう
Where did the cloud come from?
クラウドはどこから来たのでしょうか?
The elements of the cloud are not there in the end
クラウドの要素は最終的には存在しない
That's it
それでおしまい
First
初め
Clouds must have water vapor
雲には水蒸気が含まれているはずです
We say that clouds are mainly made of water
雲は主に水でできていると言いますが、
If you have another smoke cause
他に煙の原因がある場合
that doesn't count
それは意味がありません
Speaking of this water vapor
この水蒸気と言えば
you mention again
あなたはまた言及します
Here we sometimes talk about the so-called man-made cloud
ここでは、いわゆる人工雲について時々話します。
Say wow, no, we are in a drought, we need to hurry up and make rain
うわー、だめだ、私たちは干ばつに見舞われている、急いで雨を降らさなければならない、と言ってください。
But drought, what does drought mean?
でも干ばつ、干ばつってどういう意味ですか？
You are almost out of water
もうすぐ水がなくなってしまいます
True droughts are very, very rare in representations of water in the air
空気中の水の表現において、真の干ばつは非常にまれです。
absolutely not
絶対違う
How do you make rain when you have no water at all?
水がまったくないのにどうやって雨を降らせるのですか？
no way
とんでもない
So I made a skylight question, do you have any comments?
そこで天窓の質問をしましたが、何かコメントはありますか？
What is the south of the bridge, what is nothing, what is known
橋の南の壁は何ですか、何もありません、何が知られていますか
Anyone want to try it?
試してみたい人はいますか？
In fact, this is not an answer, the answer is up to you
実際、これは答えではありません、答えはあなた次第です
say what you want
何が欲しいか言ってください
I made this
これを作りました
if you have no water at all
水がまったくない場合
Even if you are a god, you cannot create clouds
神であっても雲は作れない
There is no water to make it, you are making too much of this
それを作るための水がない、あなたはこれを作りすぎています
It's useless to throw away stippling silver or something like that
点描銀とか捨てても無駄だよ
So if you want clouds, first of all, of course you must form water
したがって、雲が必要な場合は、まず第一に、もちろん水を形成する必要があります
Sometimes there is water vapor, but sometimes there is no cloud, why?
水蒸気があるときもあれば、雲がないときもありますが、なぜですか?
Because the water vapor has to be saturated to be able to
なぜなら、水蒸気が飽和する必要があるからです。
So the second one is that you have to reach saturation
2 つ目は、飽和状態に達する必要があるということです
What does it mean to be saturated?
飽和するとはどういう意味ですか?
The first one is that your water vapor content must be sufficient
1つ目は、水蒸気含有量が十分でなければならないということです。
Second, sometimes there is a lot of water vapor, you will feel very stuffy
次に、時々大量の水蒸気が発生し、非常に息苦しく感じます。
But the sky is still very bright with few and no clouds
しかし、空はまだとても明るく、雲はほとんどありません
But you feel dazed and sad, why?
でも、あなたはぼうっとして悲しくなります、なぜですか？
Because it has not reached saturation, then under what circumstances will it reach saturation
飽和していないのですが、ではどのような状況で飽和してしまうのでしょうか？
That kind of saturation has a lot to do with temperature and air temperature.
この種の飽和は、温度と気温に大きく関係します。
Therefore, the water vapor content and the temperature must be coordinated with each other.
したがって、水蒸気量と温度を調整する必要があります。
to saturate the cloud
クラウドを飽和させる
These two things are actually related to the movement of air.
この２つは実は空気の動きに関係しているのです。
What is air movement called?
空気の動きを何といいますか?
air movement that is called wind
風と呼ばれる空気の動き
Of course it's wind and water
もちろん風と水です
just one of them
そのうちの1人だけ
Usually we call horizontal movement
通常、水平移動と呼びます。
is called the wind
風と呼ばれる
The wind from east to west, from north to south
東から西、北から南の風
This is to say that the air is a horizontal movement
これは空気が水平方向に動くということです
But the air has to move up and down
しかし空気は上下に動かなければなりません
At that time it was not called the wind
あの頃は風と呼ばれていなかった
updraft or downdraft
上昇気流または下降気流
then this is
それならこれは
turn this
これを回す
talk about this up and down
このことについて上下に話し合う
general cloud formation
一般的な雲の形成
updraft relationship
上昇気流関係
relatively close
比較的近い
comparison means
比較手段
some in
いくつかの
There are of course other possibilities under individual circumstances.
もちろん、個々の状況によっては他の可能性もあります。
but the updraft
しかし上昇気流
The relationship is particularly great
特に関係は素晴らしいです
that might
その可能性があります
a little unforgettable
少し忘れられない
That is to say, the horizontal movement of the air is
つまり、空気の水平方向の動きは、
What is the difference in vertical movement?
垂直方向の動きの違いは何ですか？
This difference is very large
この差は非常に大きいです
just with you
あなただけと一緒に
usually walk on flat road
普段は平坦な道を歩きます
follow you up the mountain
山まであなたを追って
Also walk a mile to see
1マイル歩いて見ることもできます
Generally similar
概ね似たような
you see this is different
これは違うことがわかりますか
But for the air
でも空気に関しては
what is its biggest difference
その最大の違いは何ですか
its biggest difference
その最大の違いは
vertical movement of air
空気の垂直方向の動き
The change in air pressure it experiences is very large
気圧の変化が非常に大きい
if you level
レベルを上げれば
it doesn't change air pressure
空気圧は変わりません
In general, a large area
一般的に広いエリアでは、
its air pressure is about the same
気圧はほぼ同じです
So your air if in the same area
つまり、同じエリアにある場合のあなたの空気
move around
動き回る
If it is a horizontal movement
水平移動の場合
its air pressure hasn't changed
気圧は変わっていない
But if it is vertical
でも縦だと
it's totally different
それは全く違います
Ordinary air, if it runs upwards,
普通の空気が上に向かって流れていくと、
what consequences will it have
それは何をしますか
when an air goes up
空気が上がると
The pressure outside is suddenly less
外の圧力が突然減ります
we all know
私たちは皆知っています
The higher the altitude, the thinner the air
標高が高くなると空気は薄くなる
right
右
some people have mountain sickness
高山病になる人もいます
That altitude sickness is another
高山病は別です
But Takayama has a very serious
しかし、高山さんはとても真剣です。
In the mountains, the air is thinner
山の中は空気が薄いので
Some people are not used to it
慣れていない人もいる
Some people even outside
外にも人がいる
will be confused
混乱するだろう
that almost everyone
それはほぼ全員が
except for local residents
地元住民を除いて
If you go to the mountain with a height of about 5,000 meters
標高約5,000メートルの山に行くと
Almost all of them will come across more or less
それらのほぼすべては多かれ少なかれ遭遇するでしょう
So, for example, when it comes to the shoreland 13 in South America
たとえば、南米のショアランド 13 について言えば、
That place is five or six thousand meters
あの場所は五、六千メートルです
People who are not used to it can't stand that height
慣れてない人はあの高さに耐えられない
why
なぜ
Because it is very air-absorbing
空気をよく吸収するので、
The air is very attracted to you
空気はあなたにとても惹かれます
Inhaled air, the oxygen content is not enough
空気を吸うと酸素が足りない
Let you this can't produce enough heat
これでは十分な熱を生み出すことができません
So this air is getting more and more absorbed
この空気はどんどん吸収されていきます
This is a very important phenomenon
これは非常に重要な現象です
when you have a cloud of air
空気の雲があるとき
when going up
上がるとき
outside air adsorption
外気吸着
on behalf of
代表して
Because the air is supposed to have pressure, right?
だって空気には圧力があるはずですよね？
Then you are under so much pressure
それからあなたはとても大きなプレッシャーにさらされています
When it rises suddenly, the pressure outside it decreases
急激に上昇すると外側の圧力が下がります
Then it will start to expand outward
それから外側に広がり始めます
What will be the consequences of this expansion in the past?
過去のこの拡張の結果はどうなるでしょうか？
If a mass of air expands outward
空気の塊が外側に膨張すると
without other sources of heat
他の熱源なしで
It's one of the greatest possibilities it will get cold
寒くなる最大の可能性の一つです
So when an air it expands
つまり、空気が膨張すると、
As it rises and expands it cools
上昇して膨張すると冷える
Once it got cold, there was some water vapor in it
冷えると中には水蒸気が発生します
The water vapor is originally called unsaturated
水蒸気はもともと不飽和水蒸気と呼ばれます
Because under the condition of relatively high temperature
比較的高温の条件下ですので、
it does not reach saturation
飽和には達していない
But when you get cold
でも、寒くなると
It may slowly this saturation
この飽和はゆっくりと進むかもしれません
Higher and higher
高く高く
it may not necessarily reach saturation
必ずしも飽和に達するとは限らない
but maybe 90 percent saturated
でもおそらく90パーセントは飽和している
Then lift it up
それから持ち上げてください
In the end it really saturates
結局本当に飽和するんだよ
As long as the air goes up
空気が上がる限り
it's getting colder
寒くなってきました
cloud of dry air
乾燥した空気の雲
Or even a cloud of air with water vapor in it
あるいは水蒸気を含んだ空気の雲でも
it goes up
それは上がる
As long as there is no condensation
結露しない限り
it lifts a kilometer
それは1キロ持ち上げます
it's about ten degrees lower
約10度低いです
so cold
とても寒い
A cloud of air is on the ground if twenty degrees
20度であれば空気の雲が地上にある
You lifted it two thousand meters
あなたはそれを二千メートル持ち上げました
it will be zero degrees freezing point
氷点ゼロ度になります
So this is a big change
これは大きな変化です
A cloud of air rises two meters from the ground, after two thousand meters
2,000メートルを過ぎると、空気の雲が地面から2メートル上昇します
Alishan Alishan is not even 2,000 meters away
阿里山 阿里山は2,000メートルも離れていません
If a cloud of air rises from the ground to the height of Alishan
空気の雲が地面から阿里山の高みまで立ち上ったとしたら
The air inside can become freezing point.
内部の空気が氷点になる可能性があります。
then you may find it strange
そうしたら奇妙に思うかもしれない
But Alishan is not always freezing point
しかし、阿里山は常に氷点下であるわけではありません
Of course the so-called what I just said is
もちろん、それは私が今言ったことです。
That is only if the air has movement
それは空気に動きがあった場合に限る
But usually the air in Alishan is not from sports.
しかし、通常、阿里山の空気はスポーツによるものではありません。
That's another mechanic, that's another story
それは別のメカニズムです、それはまた別の話です
I won't mention it for now
今はそれについては言及しません
What I want to mention here is that
ここで言いたいのは、
If you have a cloud of air rising up the table
テーブルの上に空気の雲が立ち上っている場合
For two kilometers, it was originally twenty degrees and it became zero degrees.
２キロも最初は２０度だったのが０度になりました。
Because every kilometer it cools down ten degrees
1キロ進むごとに10度冷えるので
The same cloud of air if from a high altitude
高高度からの同じ空気の雲
sinking for some reason
何らかの理由で沈んでいる
It's going to be a day and it's going to be a very very day
それは一日になるだろう、そしてそれはとてもとても一日になるだろう
This is actually thermodynamics
これは実際には熱力学です
Thermodynamics means
熱力学の意味
Adiabatic expansion cools
断熱膨張で冷える
Adiabatic compression heats an air
断熱圧縮により空気が加熱される
Then this thing with a
それからこれは
it has something to do with your flight
それはあなたのフライトと関係があります
Usually we fly
通常、私たちは飛行します
start from the ground
地面から始める
The ground air probably has us or something
地上の空気にはおそらく私たちか何かがいるでしょう
around 1000 mbar
1000毫巴左右
You fly so high
あなたはとても高く飛びます
About 200 millibars left
残り約200ミリバール
so the air has
それで空気は
That pressure has been reduced by 1.5
その圧力は1.5減少しました
if that air
その空気なら
If the cabin doesn't pressurize the air
機内の空気が加圧されていない場合
you will feel very sad
あなたはとても悲しい気持ちになるでしょう
Because the air is too thin
空気が薄すぎるから
So the captain must use
したがって、キャプテンは使用する必要があります
big compressor
大きなコンプレッサー
press that air to
その空気を押しつける
very stressful
ストレスがたまる
almost as big as the ground
地面とほぼ同じ大きさ
sometimes say 90%
90％と言う場合もあります
and put that air in
そしてその空気を入れてください
into this cabin to let you
あなたをこの小屋に連れて行きます
let you breathe
息をさせてください
you will feel very natural
あなたはとても自然に感じるでしょう
Then we just talked about the air
それから私たちは空気について話しました
So if you compress that
それを圧縮すると
it gets hot
暑くなる
Will high altitude be able to?
高地でもできるでしょうか？
When the captain sucks in the air
船長が空気を吸うとき
Then heat it up and put it in
あとは温めてから入れます
If it doesn't put this air
この空気を入れないと
after that cold
あの寒さの後に
if the air conditioner cools it down
エアコンで涼しくなれば
The temperature is about 60 degrees
温度は約60度
everyone will be hot
みんな熱くなりますよ
Rick it's all over
リック、もう終わりだよ
So when it shakes this air into the cabin
この空気が機内に揺れるとき
It must be air-conditioned first
まずエアコンを付けなければなりません
pump this excess heat off
この余分な熱をポンプで排出します
So that consumes a very, very large amount of energy
つまり、非常に大量のエネルギーを消費します
It is to put this pressurized hot air
この加圧熱風を当てるのです
let it cool down and put it in this cabin
冷ましてからこの小屋に入れてください
So this is a very, very fuel-intensive thing
これは非常に燃料を大量に消費するものです
Even if you still have to spend some oil to deal with these problems
たとえこれらの問題に対処するために多少の石油を費やす必要があるとしても
Even if the temperature outside the cabin at that time
その時の機外の気温が変わっても、
maybe minus sixty or seventy degrees
おそらくマイナス60度か70度
It still needs to get this air to cool it down
冷却するにはまだ空気を取り込む必要がある
Relying on the outside air temperature is not enough
外気温に頼るだけでは十分ではありません
Use this air conditioner to send the cooling back in again
このエアコンを使って再び冷気を送り込みます
So this is called the expansion of the air
これを空気の膨張といいます
A very important reason for the cooling of the camp
キャンプの寒さの非常に重要な理由
So basically come this is called
基本的にこれは呼ばれます
The basic mechanism is
基本的な仕組みは、
The mechanism of forming a camp is mainly here
陣営形成の仕組みは主にここ
A cloud of air with water vapor
水蒸気を含んだ空気の雲
it cools as it goes up
上がるにつれて冷える
because of swelling
腫れのせいで
after cooling
冷却後
It will reach saturation
飽和状態に達してしまう
Once saturated
飽和したら
In theory its condensation should produce
理論的には、その凝縮によって生成されるはずです
At that time you will see the clouds come out
その時、雲が出てくるのが見えるだろう
So the picture below represents a cloud
下の写真は雲を表しています
A basic mechanism of cloud formation
雲形成の基本的な仕組み
A mass of air has no water droplets in it
空気の塊には水滴は含まれていません
but there is water vapor
でも水蒸気はある
Go up and slowly get bigger and bigger
上がってゆっくり大きくなってね
to a certain extent
ある程度まで
After they are saturated with water vapor,
水蒸気で飽和した後、
Ectopic Concrete
異所性コンクリート
By this time you should see that cloud start to come out
この頃には雲が出始めているのが見えるはずです
This is the so-called bottom of the cloud, the cloud base is starting to come out
ここがいわゆる雲の底、雲底が出始めています
And the cloud if it still has enough water in it
そして雲にまだ十分な水があれば
it will keep going up and you can see the clouds
このまま上昇していきます、そして雲が見えます
keep showing up and that weird place
現れ続ける、そしてその奇妙な場所
That is to say, once it has an air lift up
つまり、一度エアリフトアップすると、
The other air pocket below is probably coming up from the same place
下のもう一つのエアポケットもおそらく同じ場所から来ています
Because once you have one air and one goes up
なぜなら、空気が1つあれば、もう1つは上がるからです
You can easily drive other places to bring in the air
他の場所を簡単に運転して空気を取り入れることができます
And from there the new air rises up
そしてそこから新しい空気が上がっていきます
The new air has other new sources of water vapor in it
新しい空気には、他の新しい水蒸気源が含まれています
So you see a cloud rising far away
遠くまで上昇し続ける雲が見える
it's cause like this up out
それはこのようなことのせいです
So let's talk nonsense, let's watch this kind of cloud-making movie
だからくだらない話をしよう、こんな雲を作る映画を見よう
This is the so-called move of Yundi just now
これがいわゆる今のユンディの動きです
We can see the phenomenon we just mentioned
先ほど述べた現象がわかります
you see it keeps going up
上昇し続けているのがわかります
I can't see anything below why
以下に何も表示されないのはなぜですか
because of water vapor
水蒸気のせいで
Water vapor is so transparent you can't see it at all
水蒸気は透明すぎて全く見えない
In fact the air is always going up
実際、空気は常に上昇しています
But because it is transparent
でも透明なので
contains water vapor
水蒸気を含む
so you can't see
だから君には見えない
you can't see it going up
上がっていくのは見えない
In fact, there are constantly new air bags
実際、常に新しいエアバッグが登場しています
come in here
こっちに来て
then always
それからいつも
for this cloud
この雲のために
A lot of new water vapor comes out
新しい水蒸気がたくさん出てくる
If there is enough water vapor in a place,
ある場所に十分な水蒸気があれば、
Clouds can always go up
雲はいつでも上がることができる
even grown to thunder and lightning
雷と稲妻まで成長した
Why does the air go up
なぜ空気は上がるのか
wait a second
一瞬待って
The little teacher didn't want to see through everyone's past
小さな先生はみんなの過去を見抜きたくなかった
wait a minute let me see
ちょっと待って、見てみましょう
You asked exactly the topic I chose
あなたは私が選んだトピックを正確に尋ねました
Why does the air rise so high
なぜ空気はあんなに高く上がるのか
there are several theories
いくつかの理論があります
several reasons
いくつかの理由
The first is convection
まずは対流です
under the same air pressure
同じ気圧の下で
If the air in this place is warmer
この場所の空気がもっと暖かかったら
Its density will become a little lighter
濃度が少し薄くなります
So it creates a force
それで力が生まれる
For a light air is like
軽い空気はこんな感じです
an air bubble in water
水の中の気泡
relatively small density
密度比較小
So it will rise with a force
それで勢いよく上がっていきます
So this is one of the first
これは最初の 1 つです
Usually this convection is called free convection
通常、この対流は自由対流と呼ばれます
because it's all temperature dependent
すべては温度に依存するため
The first is a forced convection
1つ目は強制対流です
forced convection
強制対流
inside the weather inside the air
天気の中 空気の中
This is usually
これは通常、
For example, there is a very cold air
たとえば、とても冷たい空気があるとします。
Very cold air generally
全体的に非常に冷たい空気
it's a bit heavier
少し重いです
when it starts moving
それが動き始めるとき
There are many things moving, and the rotation of the earth will also drive it
多くのものが動いており、地球の自転もそれを動かします
It doesn't rotate at the same time as the earth
地球と同時に自転しているわけではない
It sometimes spins at a different speed than the Earth
地球とは異なる速度で回転することもあります
So anyway, it still has relative motion with the ground
とにかく、地面との相対運動はまだあります
Then once such cold air moves
そして、そのような冷たい空気が移動すると、
it will make the front lighter
フロントが軽くなります
or warmer air would be lifted by it
あるいは暖かい空気がそれによって持ち上げられるでしょう
The air, the air in front is not necessarily warmer
空気、前方の空気は必ずしも暖かいとは限りません
But it is also forced by it
しかし、それはまた、それによって強制されるものでもあります
Because of its sense of movement is forced by it
動きを強制される感覚があるため
it winds it up like an opener
まるで炉のように巻き上げられる
So it's called compulsive, compulsive uplifting
だからそれは強迫的な、強制的な高揚と呼ばれるものです
Then once the air may be reluctant
それから、一旦空気が消極的になるかもしれない
It is unwilling to rise, but because of its movement
上昇する気はありませんが、その動きのせいで
so be lifted by it
だからそれによって持ち上げられる
What should I do after I lift it up? It's the same
上げた後はどうすればいいですか? 同じです
It also expands and cools when lifted
持ち上げると膨張して冷える
Then come the clouds
それから雲が来ます
That's because this kind of movement usually has a larger scale
なぜなら、この種の運動は通常、より規模が大きいからです
So it's whole, it's a movement
それで、それが動けば、それは全体です
The whole floor has gone up
フロア全体が上がってきました
So the clouds you see act like clouds
だからあなたが見ている雲は雲のように振る舞う
Because the large area is full of clouds
広い範囲が雲だらけなので
That hair is the weather will get worse
その髪は天気が悪くなるよ
because it is a large-scale movement
大規模な動きなので
that's why i just said
だから私は今言ったんだ
If it was a high-flying
高空飛行だったら
And then it becomes the whole layer all connected
その後、すべてが接続されたレイヤー全体になります
the weather may turn bad
天気が悪くなるかもしれない
It is because of this large-scale movement
この大規模な動きがあるからこそ、
The other is volatility
もう一つはボラティリティです
Fluctuations This is usually caused by relatively small movements
変動 これは通常、比較的小さな動きによって引き起こされます。
The so-called fluctuation is like water waves
いわゆるゆらぎは水の波のようなもの
Water wave, you throw away the silk and go into the water
水の波、絹を捨てて水の中へ
Look at it spreading out in waves
波のように広がっていくのを見てください
A wave spreads out as if moving
動くように波が広がる
But the water itself is not flowing
でも水自体は流れていない
The water itself is actually just moving up and down
水自体は実際には上下に動いているだけです
But that wave looks like it's been running out
でもその波はもう終わりつつあるようだ
it just runs outside
ただ外で走っているだけです
The water itself must be flowing
水自体は流れているはずです
If you throw a piece of wood on the water
木片を水面に投げたら
The log didn't run away either
丸太も逃げなかった
The wood just moves up and down in place for a while.
木材はしばらくその場で上下に動くだけです。
So this is called volatility
これをボラティリティと呼びます
have this up and down movement
この上下の動きをします
whatever the reason
理由が何であれ
as long as you move up
あなたが上に進む限り
air will expand
空気は膨張します
will condense into clouds
凝縮して雲になるだろう
So all kinds of clouds come out
いろんな雲が出てくるので
This is a lot of individual convection generation that you saw just now
これが先ほど見た大量の個別対流発生です
This is relatively large
これは比較的大きいです
is usually you will see something like this
通常、このようなものが表示されます
The whole big cloud
大きな雲全体が
How much does it rain
どれくらい雨が降りますか
or the light rain in the big rain building
または大雨の建物の小雨
Of course not to say rainstorm
もちろん暴風雨というわけではありません
It's unlikely
それはありそうもない
If there is no wind, will there be clouds?
風がなかったら雲が出るでしょうか？
We usually talk about wind and clouds
私たちはいつも風と雲について話します
So there must be wind and there must be clouds
だから風もあるはずだし、雲もあるはずだ
But we used to have one that hurt
でも私たちにはかつて傷ついたものがあった
the great poet this du fu
偉大な詩人、この杜甫
He has a Qingzhou miscellaneous stone
彼は青州雑石を持っています
Generally twenty hands, this is the seventh hand
通常は 20 ハンドですが、これは 7 番目のハンドです
He has a boundless mountain, an isolated city, and a valley
彼は山と孤立した都市の間に広大な谷を持っている
Wu Fengyun promotes the sun
ウー・フェンユンは太陽を促進します
If you are unemployed, you will be more critical
無職ならもっと近づくよ
The two most famous of these are the
その中で最も有名なのがこの２つです
Then this unemployed is getting closer
するとこの失業者が近づいてくる
Then this is astronomical
そうするとこれは天文学的な数字になります
Leave it to the people at the astronomical institute to explain
説明は天文研究所の人に任せてください
A college student from Houhou Earth Institute can also explain
ホウホウ地球研究所の大学生も解説します
then i want to explain
それでは説明したいと思います
Will no wind and cloud block
風も雲も遮らないだろう
If there is no wind, will it
風がなかったらそうなるのかな
will the clouds come out
雲が出てくるでしょうか
that's certainly possible
それは確かに可能です
Because I mentioned it for a long time
長々と言いましたので
It doesn't have to be windy
風が強い必要はない
you can still have clouds
まだ雲が残っている可能性があります
pop up
現れる
this is for volatility
これはボラティリティのためです
it's just at dusk
ちょうど夕暮れ時です
You can see that there are actually many fluctuations in the air
実際に空気にはゆらぎがたくさんあることがわかります
Air is like water
空気は水のようなもの
same thing
同じこと
moving from time to time
時々移動する
What if the air humidity is just right?
空気の湿度が適切であればどうなるでしょうか?
You see just created a cloud
クラウドが作成されたことがわかります
Usually this tail is invisible
通常、この尻尾は見えません
because it's usually thin
普通に薄いから
Good luck after giving birth on this day
この日は出産後も頑張ってね
The sun just shines from that angle
その角度からは太陽が輝いています
show you this thin eye
この細い目を見せて
So it should be seen that this place is actually a large part of the whole wave
したがって、この場所が実際には波全体の大部分を占めていることがわかるはずです。
Just at the place where the height of the wave is the highest, where the wave wind
ちょうど波の高さが一番高い場所、波風が吹く場所。
some clouds will come out
少し雲が出てくるでしょう
Why do clouds form where the wind blows?
風が吹くと雲ができるのはなぜですか?
Because the place where the wave is square is of course where the air rises
波が四角い場所は当然空気が上昇する場所だから
Usually an ancient place like this is where the air sinks
通常、このような古い場所は空気が沈む場所です
There are no clouds in most places
ほとんどの場所で雲がありません
this day is special
この日は特別です
It's more humid
もっと湿気が多いです
So there will be clouds even in this place that day
だからあの日はこの場所にも雲があるだろう
But this place the clouds are thicker
でもここは雲が厚い
So this cloud is a cloud produced by fluctuations
つまりこの雲はゆらぎによって生み出された雲なのです
it often looks like a lens
レンズのように見えることが多い
So this is called lenticular
これをレンチキュラーと呼びます
lenticular cloud
レンチキュラークラウド
This is really a lenticular cloud
これは本当にレンズ状の雲です
Sometimes you can see the sky full of clouds like this
たまにはこんな雲だらけの空も見えるよね
like a lens
レンズのように
like a thick slice
厚切りのような
In fact, this is all generated by waves.
実はこれはすべて波によって生み出されているのです。
This is really like playing without wind and clouds
これは本当に風も雲もなくプレーしているようなものです
you can
あなたはできる
I know it why these two doses learn well
この 2 回の投与量がよく学習する理由がわかりました
In the last section, this somewhat mysterious place
最後のセクションでは、このちょっと不思議な場所を
Because it is written in such an unofficial place
非公式なところに書いてあるので
It mentions that there is no wind but there are clouds, coming out
風はないけど雲が出ていると書いてあります。
You feel as if there is no movement, but the enemy suddenly appears
ほら、何も動いていないように見えますが、突然敵が現れます
There's this air of absurdity coming out of your body
不条理な空気が体から出てくる
You can imagine this place
この場所を想像することができます
It seems that your officer is here, then on the opposite side of the mountain or when
あなたの警官はここにいるようですが、そのときは山の反対側にいるか、
This evil slave's Qibing regiment popped up, no wind and shadow left the fortress
この邪悪な奴隷のキビン連隊が現れ、風も影も要塞から出なかった
I'm not saying I believe the name of the flying saucer, it may be a so-called flying saucer
空飛ぶ円盤の名前を信じているわけではありません、いわゆる空飛ぶ円盤かもしれません
But our dude drinks decently, it's all right
でもうちの奴はちゃんと飲んでるから大丈夫だよ
But this kind of cloud in the broken mirror sometimes looks like this
でも割れた鏡に映るこの雲は時々こんな風に見えるんだ
It seems that suddenly a big tide rises and appears in the sky
突然大きな潮が満ちて空に現れたように見える
Then this is exactly the relationship that should fluctuate, especially in the mountains
そうすると、特に山では、まさにこの関係が変動するはずです。
back then it would have a lot of these fluctuations
当時はこうした変動がたくさんあっただろう
This kind of fluctuation will produce this kind of cloud if the kind of conditions are just right
こういうゆらぎ、条件が合えばこういう雲が生まれる
This is often geographical
これは多くの場合地理的なものです
Certain geographies are particularly prone to such clouds
特定の地域では特にこのような雲が発生しやすい
so you want to see ufo
だからUFOを見たいのですか
It looks especially good in that place
その場所は特によく見えます
This is the same lenticular cloud
これは同じレンチキュラークラウドです
it has several layers
いくつかの層があります
It's the same kind of fluctuation not just one layer
一層じゃなくて同じようなゆらぎだよ
sometimes several layers
場合によっては複数の層
Sometimes it looks very, very spectacular
時々それはとてもとても壮観に見える
This will just go here and look up
これはここに行って上を見るだけです
This is actually very, very many
これは実際には非常に多くの
Very, very beautiful clouds can be seen
とてもとても綺麗な雲が見えます
And I just talked for a long time
そして、私はただ長い間話しました
No weather
天候不順
So if there is no wind
それで風がなければ
Clouds will still come
雲はまだ出てきます
so the wind blows
だから風が吹く
This is just a general statement
これは単なる一般論です
It's okay without the wind
風がなくても大丈夫
that's the other way around now
それは今は逆です
If there is wind, do the clouds have to move?
風が吹けば雲も動くのでしょうか？
After each use, after psychology is disassembled, we may or may not move
使用するたびに、心理が解体された後、私たちは動くかもしれないし、動かないかもしれない
It does not move sometimes, why? You can watch this video
確かに時々動かないことがありますが、なぜですか?このビデオをご覧ください。
The wind is clearly blowing
はっきりと風が吹いています
But some power supplies don't seem to want to run away
しかし、一部の電源は暴走したくないようです
Like this teacher here on this mountain
この山のこの先生のように
One side is bigger and the other side is small, but it seems that he is not willing to run away
片方は大きくて片方は小さいですが、逃げる気はないようです
isn't it a bit strange
ちょっと変じゃないですか
So if there is no wind blowing, will the cloud not move? Is it possible to not move?
では、風が吹かなければ雲は動かないのでしょうか?動かないということはあり得るのでしょうか?
like this case
このケースのように
The wind is clearly leaving, the wind is blowing
風は明らかに去っていく、風が吹いている
But that means I don't want to run away
でもそれは逃げたくないということ
is it possible
出来ますか
But that's what the movie is about
でもそれがこの映画の話なんだよ
Actually what's going on
実際、何が起こっているのか
This is also a wave shadow
これも波影です
How does this wave shadow come about?
この波の影はどうやって生まれるのでしょうか？
Because when the wind blows over the mountain, there are many waves
山の上に風が吹くと波がたくさんあるから
so where the wind blows
だから風が吹くところへ
cloud is born
雲が生まれる
because the air is reborn
空気が生まれ変わるから
Just when this wave is generated
ちょうどこの波が発生するとき
This wave is called Standing Wave.
この波を定在波といいます。
when it blows over this mountain
この山を越えて吹くとき
The wind of that wave is always in the same place
その波の風はいつも同じ場所にある
So every time this moisture-laden air
だからこの湿気を含んだ空気が来るたびに
As soon as it blows over this mountain
この山を越えるとすぐに
in the same place
同じ場所で
it also produces a wind
風も生み出す
where is a wave of wind
風の波はどこですか
So the air goes up in that same place
同じ場所で空気が上がる
after this wind
この風の後に
Air rises down in the same place
空気は同じ場所に上昇します
Once it goes down, it rises into the clouds and disappears.
一度下がると雲の中に上がって消えていきます。
Once it goes up the cloud appears
上がると雲が現れる
So in fact that cloud is not the original cloud
つまり、実際にはそのクラウドは元のクラウドではありません
That cloud is different from that water vapor
あの雲はあの水蒸気とは違う
If you make a mark for each of the water vapor, say
それぞれの水蒸気に印を付けると、次のように言います。
This water vapor is fake and this is mobile
この水蒸気は偽物で、これはモバイルです
I don't know where the water vapor in that Chiayi bottle went.
嘉義の瓶から出た水蒸気がどこへ行ったのかは分かりません。
But it looks like you're talking about the same cloud
しかし、あなたは同じクラウドについて話しているようです
that's just an illusion
それはただの幻想です
In fact, all clouds are illusions
実は雲はすべて幻なのです
When talking about age, everyone is actually an illusion
年齢について話すとき、実際には誰もが幻想です
So in biologists say
それで生物学者は言う
Our cells seem to be replaced every seven years.
私たちの細胞は7年ごとに入れ替わるようです。
So every seven years I am actually a different person
つまり、7年ごとに私は実際には別の人間になるのです
So I used to say that the American one
だから私はよく言った、アメリカのものは
A swap called that Simpson
シンプソンと呼ばれる交換
Oggy Simpson he all scrubs his wife
オギー・シンプソン、彼は妻を徹底的にこすります
if in case he is convicted
万が一彼が有罪判決を受けた場合
He can be hidden for seven years and then run out
彼は7年間隠蔽されてから逃げ出すことができる
say I'm different
私は違うと言う
I'm not the original one
私はオリジナルではありません
At critical times, I can say that what I want to judge is not
大事な時に言えるのは、自分が判断したいのはそうではないということだ
not your body
あなたの体ではありません
It's who you are, who you are as Oggy Simpson
それがあなたです、オギー・シンプソンとしてのあなたです
But the cloud really isn't it's not a solid thing
でもクラウドって本当は固体じゃないんだよ
So the components inside him are actually changing all the time.
つまり、彼の中の構成要素は実際には常に変化しているのです。
The cloud you'll see isn't really a constant thing
あなたが見る雲は実際には一定のものではありません
The thing itself is always changing
物事自体は常に変化している
What you see doesn't change is the shape of that thing
君が見ているのは変わらないその物の形
just a pattern, a form
ただのパターン、形
You always think that thing, this cloud is not
あなたはいつもそんなことを考えていますが、この雲はそうではありません
That's just the form of that cloud
それはまさにその雲の形です
So this thing is a very important point to understand the movement of clouds
これは雲の動きを理解する上で非常に重要なポイントです
So the following pattern is also such a phenomenon
したがって、次のパターンもそのような現象です
The water vapor has already been
水蒸気はすでに存在しています
You can see that the cloud doesn't seem to go anywhere else.
雲が他にどこにも行っていないように見えることがわかります。
It's just been moving up and down, but it's not
上下に動いているだけですが、そうではありません
That cloud has already gone away
その雲はもう消えてしまった
I don't know where the water went
水がどこへ行ったのか分かりません
What you see is actually a completely different cloud
実際に見えているのはまったく異なる雲です
That water vapor is already new water vapor
その水蒸気はもう新しい水蒸気です
For the same reason, when you watch the sign reports on TV, you can see
同じ理由で、テレビの兆候レポートを見ると、次のようになります。
Where does a certain typhoon come from?
ある台風はどこから来るのでしょうか？
A huge cloud, like a whirlpool, and move here
渦のような巨大な雲がここに動く
That's just the form of the vortex running
それはまさに渦が走る姿だ
I don't know where the water went
水がどこへ行ったのか分かりません
Those waters have already finished raining
その水はもう雨が終わった
There is new water coming out
新しい水が出てきています
It's just that the water runs into the same whirlpool all day long
ただ水は一日中同じ渦に流れ込むだけだ
so it looks like
だからそれはのように見える
The clouds seem to have the same shape
雲は同じ形に見える
In fact, the water in those clouds has already been replaced with a lot of new ones.
実際、それらの雲の中の水はすでにたくさんの新しいものに置き換えられています。
completely different
全然違う
so the point is
それでポイントは
One of the things you need to know when looking at the cloud
クラウドを見るときに知っておくべきことの 1 つ
OK, just now we mentioned that the vertical movement is mainly related to the generation of clouds
OK、先ほど垂直方向の動きが主に雲の生成に関係していると言いました。
Then let's say the level will not
それでは、レベルが上がらないとしましょう。
Did you guess wrong about the level?
レベルの推測が間違っていませんか？
because there is no change in air pressure
気圧の変化がないので
So the possibility of creating a cloud
つまり、クラウドを作成する可能性があります
doesn't seem too big
あまり大きくないようです
Is there any objection to this
これに異論はありますか
Is there any objection? No one seems to object. Strange
何か異論はありますか?誰も異論はないようです。不思議です。
Everyone agrees very much today
今日はみんなとても同意
In fact, a horizontal pass can also cause clouds
実は横パスも曇りの原因になる
have you seen this
これを見たことがありますか
If you go to the show of this plane
この飛行機のショーに行くなら
Panel sometimes sees that the aircraft performance is very slow
パネルは時々航空機のパフォーマンスが非常に遅いと認識します
when suddenly it's fast
突然速くなったとき
Suddenly, as soon as I dodged and won, I was captured in a certain place on the plane
突然、避けて勝った瞬間、飛行機のとある場所に捕らえられてしまった
This is a positive wave
これはポジティブな波動です
Why is it called Zhengbo
なぜ鄭波と呼ばれるのか
Because it's generated in exactly the same place as the so-called positive wave wind
いわゆる正波風と全く同じ場所で発生するので
Sharkfron
シャークフロン
It is exactly the same shape as its positive wave
正の波動と全く同じ形です
and this place is
そしてこの場所は
When an aircraft accelerates to just supersonic speed
航空機がちょうど超音速まで加速するとき
That's when this cloud was born
このクラウドが生まれたのはそのときです
this is weird
これは奇妙だ
How did this cloud come about
この雲はどのようにして生まれたのか
The two elements of the cloud we just talked about
先ほど説明したクラウドの 2 つの要素
one is water vapor
一つは水蒸気です
one is saturated
1つは飽和しています
so you have a way to saturate it
だからそれを飽和させる方法があります
In fact, both horizontal and vertical
実は横も縦も
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
So this horizontal movement
つまり、この水平方向の動きは、
How can it be saturated?
どうすれば飽和状態になれるのでしょうか？
When an aircraft accelerates beyond the factor
航空機が基準を超えて加速したとき
For a while because of the movement of the plane itself
飛行機自体の動きによりしばらくの間
faster than its rising wave
上昇波よりも速く
the one with its air
空気のあるもの
The air originally had a rising wave, the so-called compression wave
空気にはもともと上昇波、いわゆる圧縮波がありました。
when you generate this
これを生成するとき
your wave source
あなたの波動源
When the speed of this wave is faster than yours
この波の速度があなたの波より速いとき
the wave generated at that time
その時に生まれた波動
That's no ordinary rising wave
それは普通の上昇波ではありません
that's a positive wave
それはポジティブな波動です
That positive wave causes the air to expand dramatically
そのポジティブな波動が空気を劇的に膨張させる
Usually the rising wave and the expansion are very small
通常、上昇波と拡大は非常に小さいです
But this positive wave suddenly
でもこのポジティブな波は突然
In a very short time it swells very much
あっという間にかなり膨らみます
As long as the air expands
空気が膨張する限り
right away
すぐに
Rapid expansion produces rapid cooling
急速な膨張により急速な冷却が生じる
If you were this
あなたがこれだったら
If the moisture content is sufficient
水分量が十分であれば
so rapidly expanding
とても急速に拡大している
let it happen now
今すぐそれを起こさせてください
big ticket cloud
一大票雲
His shape is exactly the same as the shape of the positive wave
彼の形は正の波動の形と全く同じです
So this quantity is the so-called positive wave
したがって、この量はいわゆる正の波動です
So he this if he keeps going at this supersonic speed
つまり、彼がこの超音速で進み続けるとこうなる
That Yun Changchang has been following him
ユン・チャンチャンが彼を追いかけていること
Because he looked like he hung up a pilot
パイロットを吊るしたように見えたから
It's like running for a long time
まるで長時間走っているようだ
Sometimes you fly over that drier place
時々君はあの乾いた場所の上を飛ぶんだ
the cloud disappears
雲が消える
The certifier is about to emerge
認証者がもうすぐ登場します
you say watch that kind of movie
そういう映画を見ろって言うの
And he sometimes does not practice local
そして彼は地元で練習しないこともあります
Sometimes there are two different places
場合によっては2つの異なる場所があることもあります
As long as that place exceeded the speed of sound at that time
あの時音速を超えた場所である限り
you will see this cloud
この雲が見えるでしょう
So the same positive wave cloud
つまり、同じポジティブな波動の雲
so this is horizontal movement
これは水平方向の動きです
accounting is fair
会計は公正です
Is there anything other than this word?
この言葉以外に何かあるでしょうか？
This positive wave supersonic
このポジティブな超音速波動
Is there anyone climbing here?
ここに登る人はいますか？
does anyone like mountain climbing
登山が好きな人はいますか
Has anyone seen this cloud before?
この雲を見たことがありますか?
In fact, Yushan sometimes has this kind of cloud
実は玉山には時々こんな雲が出ることがあります。
This is Benechal and this is Qi Yun
こちらはベネシャル、こちらはチーユン
because it will be like a Qizi
Qiziみたいになるから
Usually this cloud is where it's downwind
通常、この雲は風下にあります
Especially an isolated mountain like this
特にこんな孤立した山は
particularly likely
特に可能性が高い
As long as this mountain is not too long
この山が長くない限り
like a ridge
尾根のように
as long as it is relatively isolated
比較的孤立している限り
and there are no other mountains nearby
近くに他に山はありません
block until it has a high probability of producing this cloud
この雲を生成する可能性が高くなるまでブロックします
like the world's tallest everest
像世界最高峰的Everest
Also often have this kind of Benechal
この種のベネシャルもよくあります
generate this cloud
このクラウドを生成する
If you are climbing
登山中なら
you see this cloud
この雲が見えますね
you plan not to go up
あなたは上がらないつもりですか
better
より良い
why
なぜ
because when you see this cloud
なぜならこの雲を見ると
it means the weather is not going to be good
それは天気が良くないことを意味します
at least the wind will be strong
少なくとも風は強くなるだろう
so you were climbing
それであなたは登っていました
can be quite dangerous
非常に危険な可能性があります
especially the mountain
特に山
That mountain wind is so strong
あの山の風はとても強いです
but how did it come about
しかし、それはどのようにして起こったのでしょうか
Because usually you want enough wind speed
通常は十分な風速が必要なため
windy enough
十分に風が強い
Of course there is enough water
もちろん水も十分にあります
when the wind is strong enough
風が十分に強いとき
when you blow through a main obstacle
主要な障害物を吹き抜けるとき
in front of the obstacle
障害物の前で
it is a high pressure area
高圧地域です
But behind this obstacle
しかし、この障害の背後には
is a low pressure area
低気圧地域です
So of course when an air goes from high pressure to low pressure
もちろん、空気が高圧から低圧に変わるとき
it also swells
それも膨らむ
it would have been denser
もっと濃かったでしょう
Once in this low pressure area it has no limit
この低圧領域に入ると制限はありません
as the air rises
空気が上昇するにつれて
At this time, the air will also expand
このとき空気も膨張します
when the air expands
空気が膨張すると
it will cool down
涼しくなるでしょう
possible after cooling
冷却後も可能
saturate the water with air
水を空気で飽和させる
So you have this cloud
この雲があります
Of course there are one or two other causes of cloud formation
もちろん、雲の形成には他にも 1 つまたは 2 つの原因があります。
But the most important cause
しかし、最も重要な原因は
It's because of the wind inside
室内に風のせいだ
so why do you see clouds
それで、なぜ雲が見えるのですか
Almost every time
ほぼ毎回
just behind this mountain
この山のすぐ後ろに
just one
一つだけ
like a cloud floating in the ocean
海に浮かぶ雲のように
the reason for it
その理由
That's it
それでおしまい
so this is another
それで、これは別のものです
Similarly, Ma Dehong in Switzerland is particularly easy to produce
同様に、スイスの馬徳紅は特に生産が簡単です。
Because he is a particularly isolated mountain
特に孤立した山だから
So he often has a big flag
だから彼はよく大きな旗を持っている
hanging on his flagpole
彼の旗竿にぶら下がっている
it will
そうなる
So while horizontal motion is not the most important cause of clouds
したがって、水平方向の動きは雲の最も重要な原因ではありませんが、
But he can also generate clouds
しかし、彼は雲を生成することもできます
Just gave two examples
2つの例を挙げました
OK
OK
So we conclude that the shape of the cloud is mainly due to the flow of air
したがって、雲の形は主に空気の流れによるものであると結論付けられます。
Clouds are formed in the air
空気中に雲が発生する
If the air flow pattern does not change
エアフローパターンが変わらない場合
The shape of the cloud will not change
雲の形は変わらない
look at those wave shadows
あの波影を見てください
it stays that way
それはそのままです
Why? Because the shape of the air flow will not change
なぜかというと、空気の流れの形が変わらないからです。
And if the air flows in the wrong way
そして、空気が間違った方向に流れた場合、
and not moving
そして動かない
Instant air is moving
瞬間的な空気が動いている
the cloud doesn't move
雲は動かない
Because the cloud is in this form only
クラウドはこの形だけだから
The cloud of the cloud actually represents the kind of
雲の雲は実際に次のようなものを表しています。
a pattern
一種pattern
So the wind blows that cloud whatever you want
だから風はその雲をあなたが望むままに吹き飛ばします
It's not moving at all
全然動いてないよ
This is the most important point of watching the movement of clouds
ここが雲の動きを見る最大のポイントです
OK, come on down, we usually say that clouds condense when they reach saturation.
OK、さあ、私たちは通常、雲は飽和に達すると凝結すると言います。
Right or wrong because common sense doesn't seem to be wrong
常識は間違っていないようなので正しいか間違っているか
But seriously, it's not quite right.
しかし真剣に言うと、それは完全に正しくありません。
Because the so-called so-called saturation is 100%
いわゆる彩度が100%なので
Relatively moderate and you can reach saturation
比較的適度で飽和状態に達する可能性がある
The so-called relative moderate is under a specific temperature and pressure
いわゆる「相対的中程度」とは、特定の温度と圧力下にあります。
Ratio of current steam to saturated steam
電流蒸気と飽和蒸気の比率
that is called relative moderation
それは相対的中程度と呼ばれます
Saturated steam is generally determined by temperature
飽和蒸気は一般に温度によって決まります
under a certain temperature
一定の温度の下で
This steam that needs to be balanced on your level
この蒸気はあなたのレベルでバランスを取る必要があります
That is called saturated steam
それを飽和水蒸気といいます
British scientist Teklin Kelvin
イギリスの科学者テクリン・ケルビン
he proposes a
彼は提案します
He proves to you that when your relative numbers are hundreds of words
彼は、あなたの相対的な数が数百語になるとき、それを証明します。
I will give you a drop of water, I promise that the drop of water must be multiplied
あなたに一滴の水を差し上げます、その一滴の水は何倍にもなるはずだと約束します
And it must be multiplied until all of them disappear, do you want to believe it or not
そして、それらがすべて消えるまでそれは増幅されなければなりません、信じたいですか、信じたくないですか
We usually say that I don't believe it, we have already said in textbooks
私たちはいつも「信じられない」と言いますが、すでに教科書で話されています。
Humidity is 100 words, it is starting to be lingering, but CAMMAN says it is wrong
湿気は百の言葉、それは残り始めていますが、CAMMANはそれは間違っていると言います
Humidity, the water droplet should be increased, I didn't believe it at the beginning
湿度は百の言葉、水滴は増加して溶解するはずです、最初は信じていませんでした
But when you go to the partner company, it seems that you don't have a big face
でも協力会社に行くと大きな顔してないみたい
Later, many people did a lot of experiments, and it is indeed the case
その後、多くの人が多くの実験を行い、実際にそうなりました。
Indeed, it is indeed multiplied, and I later found out that our ordinary water droplets
確かに、それは確かに増殖しており、後で知ったのですが、私たちの普通の水滴は
That's a few different kinds of water droplets, our normal water droplets
それはいくつかの異なる種類の水滴です、私たちの通常の水滴です
It's not clean enough at all, if the water droplet is clean
水滴がきれいなら全然きれいじゃない
The water droplet of your relative number of hundreds of characters will increase and dissolve
あなたの相対数百文字の水滴が増えて溶けていきます
This has been proved by many experiments
これは多くの実験によって証明されています
Then under what circumstances that water drop
では、どのような状況で水が落ちるのかというと、
won't multiply
増えません
The water drops will get off, there must be something else
水滴は落ちます、何かがあるはずです
not just water
水だけではない
Many experiments have proved that
多くの実験がそれを証明しました
just below our surface environment
私たちの表面環境のすぐ下に
if you only have water vapor
水蒸気しかないなら
nothing else the air will stick
他に何も空気がくっつかない
you smoked it very clean
あなたはとてもきれいに吸ったね
Use a filter to get it very clean
フィルターをかけてとてもきれいにします
Are you probably 300% or 400% relatively
あなたはおそらく 300% か 400% ですか?
you will have to condense out
凝縮する必要があります
Otherwise there would be no condensation
そうしないと結露が発生しません
Usually our air is not so clean
通常、私たちの空気はそれほどきれいではありません
There's a lot of stuff in there
そこにはたくさんのものが入っています
a bunch of these little particles
これらの小さな粒子の束
That kind of small particle is the so-called condensation here
そのような小さな粒子がここでのいわゆる凝結です
Usually you need the help of these little particles
通常、これらの小さな粒子の助けが必要です
Water vapor can only be used when the relative number is 100%.
水蒸気は相対数が 100% の場合にのみ使用できます。
just started to condense
凝縮し始めたばかり
Otherwise it would be so-called oversatisfaction
そうしないといわゆる過満足になってしまいます
it will go all the way to 300 400
300 400まで行くだろう
Then it starts to condense into water
その後、水に凝縮し始めます
So this is called condensation
これを結露といいます
So it's important to say
だから言うことが重要です
Clouds will form in our air
私たちの空気中に雲ができるでしょう
almost certain to have this condensation
ほぼ確実にこの結露が発生します
Otherwise there would be no clouds
そうでなければ雲は存在しないでしょう
Very clean air and probably no clouds
空気はとてもきれいで、おそらく雲はありません
So it must be clean without air
したがって、空気がなくてもきれいでなければなりません
There must be some fine dust in the air
空気中には細かい塵が浮いているはずだ
Some dust particles create this cloud
いくつかの塵の粒子がこの雲を作成します
So this thing is called condensation nuclei
したがって、これらのものは凝縮核と呼ばれます
The most common condensation nuclei are
最も一般的な縮合核は次のとおりです。
Leuphane-Anderlein
ルーファン アンデルライン
This Sodium Ammonium Sulphate
この硫酸アンモニウムナトリウム
And the usual severity
そしていつもの厳しさ
Ordinary is less severe
普通はそれほど深刻ではない
Most of this flow cream
このフロークリームのほとんどは
if the cloud continues to grow
クラウドが成長し続けるなら
will turn into rain
雨に変わるだろう
become raindrops
雨粒になる
I used Google to find some cartoonists
Googleを使って漫画家を探しました
raindrops have any opinion
雨粒には意見がある
Which one of the raindrops do you think is the best?
どの雨粒が一番いいと思いますか?
or which one is the worst
それともどれが一番悪いのか
In fact, they all look the same
実はどれも同じに見えるんです
He must have painted them all the same.
彼はそれらをすべて同じように描いたに違いありません。
But the most important point is that the raindrops here are all drawn wrong
しかし最も重要な点は、ここの雨粒はすべて間違って描かれているということです
raindrops don't look like that
雨粒はそうは見えない
this is not a raindrop
これは雨粒ではありません
this is tears
これは涙です
This is a teardrop
これは涙のしずくです
Raindrops are not like this
雨粒はこんなものじゃない
Apparently these cartoonists have never seen raindrops like this
どうやらこの漫画家たちはこのような雨粒を見たことがないようです
what raindrops look like
雨粒はどのように見えるか
The raindrops are actually quite steep
雨粒は実際にはかなり急です
You said to use that kind of quick photo
そんな簡単な写真を使うって言ってたよね
When it rains, take pictures of the raindrops
雨が降ったら雨粒の写真を撮りましょう
This is an example
これは一例です
Below the raindrops is flat
雨粒の下は平ら
almost flat
ほぼ平らな
sometimes farther
時にはもっと遠くへ
But most of them are cheaper
でもほとんどがもっと安いです
farther up
さらに上へ
This is the image of real raindrops and this is what it looks like
これは実際の雨滴の画像で、次のようになります。
You see, none of the cartoonists came out with a drawing board
ほら、漫画家は誰も画板を持っていなかったんです
But if you know slip mechanics
でも、滑り力学を知っていれば
That's the only thing that's reasonable
それが唯一合理的なことだ
That's exactly what it looks like
まさにその通りです
Indeed the image of raindrops
まさに雨粒のイメージ
It's exactly the shape of this barbarian head
まさにこの野蛮人の頭の形だ
And here's one that we're doing experiments in a wind tunnel
これは風洞実験を行っているものです
You can put a bead of water in a vertical wind tunnel
垂直風洞に水の玉を入れることができる
there's wind blowing up below
下では風が吹いています
You can use this as long as the technology and equipment are in high condition
技術と設備が良好な状態であればご利用いただけます
You can stop this droplet in the air
この飛沫を空中で止めることができる
let it stop there
そこでやめさせてください
Even in front of your eyes you can watch it stew for two hours
2時間煮込む様子を目の前でも見られる
if you want
お望みならば
We did this kind of experiment before I was at this time
私がこの時になる前にこの種の実験をしました
This one is 1 to 3mm
これは1～3mmです
and no power plant
そして発電所もない
In addition, there are cases for power plants
また、発電所の場合もあります。
But today I won't have the chance to tell you
でも今日はそれを話す機会がありません
This drop of water floating in the air
空中に浮かぶこの水滴は
Do you see if its shape is that of a brute?
その形が獣の形であるかどうかわかりますか？
blow up
爆破する
The same is equivalent to this raindrop
この雨粒も同じです
like falling from above
上から落ちてくるような
then i make it stop there
それから私はそこで停止させます
adjust from time to time
時々調整する
speed of air
空気の速度
Because the water droplets will gradually increase in size after a long time.
なぜなら、水滴は時間の経過とともに徐々に大きくなるからです。
so it gets smaller
だから小さくなる
So its speed will change
それで速度が変わります
This one is through a glass pie
これはガラスのパイを通してです
Then I want to raise the stage here
それではここでステージを上げていきたいと思います
I'll mention it here
ここで言及しておきます
mentioned water of course, but rain if it's high enough
もちろん水について言及しましたが、十分な高さであれば雨が降ります
There is not only water in it, of course there is also ice, that is what will be mentioned below
そこには水だけではなく、もちろん氷もあります。それについては後述します。
So that's the water drop that's all in the air in october four
これが 10 月 4 日に空中に浮いた水滴です
So I hope everyone will go back after watching this today
なので今日はこれを見て皆さん帰っていただければと思います
The next time it rains, you have to think about it all over your head, that's right
次に雨が降ったら、頭の中で考えなくてはいけない そうだよ
OK, so when the temperature in that cloud drops below zero degrees Celsius
そうですね、その雲の温度が摂氏 0 度以下に下がったら
Water vapor and water droplets in clouds may start to freeze into ice
雲の中の水蒸気と水滴が凍って氷になり始める可能性があります
Water droplets may freeze into ice, but if water vapor freezes directly
水滴が凍って氷になることもありますが、水蒸気が直接凍ると
That is a freezing phenomenon called sublimation
それは昇華と呼ばれる凍結現象です
This is just common sense, common sense is often not the truth
これは単なる常識です、常識は真実ではないことがよくあります
When observing in the clouds
雲の中を観察する場合
The temperature of its clouds is often minus 20 degrees
雲の温度はマイナス20度になることもある
As a result, the water is still low
そのため、水位はまだ低い状態です
The water inside is still low, and it still hasn't turned into ice
中の水はまだ少なく、まだ氷になっていません。
That water is too cold
その水は冷たすぎる
That supercooled water is often very, very common.
この過冷却水は、非常に一般的なものです。
So what we often observe below zero is to say
つまり、私たちが氷点下でよく観察していることは、次のようなことです。
minus ten to twenty degrees
マイナス10度から20度
Sometimes even to minus 40 degrees
時にはマイナス40度になることもあります
it will really turn into ice
本当に氷になってしまう
Otherwise it is often still a lot of water
そうしないと、まだ大量の水が残っていることがよくあります
and it's bad to say
そして言うのは悪いです
you know it's water
あなたはそれが水であることを知っています
But once your plane flies over
でも飛行機が上空を通過すると
it may turn to ice in no time
あっという間に氷になってしまうかもしれない
and as soon as it flies past
そしてそれが通り過ぎるとすぐに
It's the water that sticks to the wings of your plane
飛行機の翼に付着するのは水です
and can't get rid of
そして取り除くことができません
And once the cloud is thick enough,
そして、雲が十分に厚くなると、
you keep flying
あなたは飛び続けます
Its ice is getting thicker
氷が厚くなってきています
In the end, the shape of your wings completely changed
やがて君の翼の形はすっかり変わってしまった
It's that changed shape, that plane
それは形を変えた、あの飛行機です
won't get up at all
まったく起きません
Because the wings of an airplane must have a certain shape
飛行機の翼には決まった形が必要だから
it can go up
それは上がるこ​​とができます
When your airplane wings are covered with ice like this
こうやって飛行機の翼が氷で覆われたら
you'll come down again
あなたはまた降りてくるでしょう
Many plane crashes are due to the phenomenon of aircraft crews
飛行機事故の多くは航空機乗務員の現象によるものです
The machine is on the paper list
このマシンは用紙リストに載っています
The most serious machine soldier does not mean that the soldier is directly glued to it
最も深刻な機械兵士は、兵士がそれに直接接着されているという意味ではありません
but this supercooled water
でもこの過冷却水は
super cold water
超冷たい水
But once he touches this solid surface
しかしひとたび彼がこの固い表面に触れると、
He immediately formed an army
彼はすぐに軍隊を組織した
and can't take it off
そして脱げない
he's so clingy
彼はとてもしがみついている
that is the most dangerous situation
それは最も危険な状況です
so under what circumstances
それで、どのような状況で
he will form an army
彼は軍隊を結成するだろう
same as coagulation
凝固と同じ
He wants another thing called a soldier box
彼はソルジャーボックスという別の物を望んでいる
He can do it only if he gets a soldier
彼は兵士を手に入れた場合にのみそれができる
He needs a soldier box before he can form a soldier
兵士を編成するには兵士ボックスが必要です
The so-called ordinary weapon box often processes ordinary things
いわゆる普通の武器箱は普通のものを処理することが多い
just ordinary sand
普通の砂
just ordinary dust
ただの普通の塵
So you think that this thing should be all over the sky
だから君は、これが空の上にあるはずだと思っているんだね
not all over the sky
空全体ではない
Ordinary sand is actually big
普通の砂って実は大きいんです
Ordinary sand means maybe
普通の砂ということは、おそらく
fraction of a millimeter
ミリ単位の
You gotta get this thing up that high
これをあんな高いところまで上げないといけない
it is not going up
上がっていない
so be slow
だからゆっくりしてください
So the high altitude is actually
つまり、標高が高いのは実際には
The sky is clean
空はきれいです
so you have these things that condense into ice
凍結するものがあります
In fact, it is full
実は満員です
But once it freezes
でも一度凍ってしまうと
it's quite beautiful
とても美しいです
You can see many different
いろいろ見ることができますよ
snowflake shape
雪の結晶の形
Here is an example for you
ここに例があります
Snowflakes usually mentioned in camp
キャンプでよく言われる雪の結晶
Many ice spirits collide
たくさんの氷の精霊がぶつかり合う
it combines with each other
それは互いに結合します
become the so-called Goose Feather University
いわゆるグースフェザー大学になる
Have you seen Goose Feather University
グースフェザー大学を見たことがありますか？
It's not actually a piece of ice
実は氷じゃないんです
several different pieces of ice
いくつかの異なる氷
even hundreds of pieces of different years up
たとえ何年も経った何百もの作品であっても
That is the so-called Goose Feather University
それがいわゆるガチョウの羽大学です
something like this
このようなもの
this piece
この作品
In fact, there are probably dozens of different
実際にはおそらく何十種類もあるでしょう
The little ice spirits are all connected together
小さな氷の精霊たちはみんなつながっている
caused
所造成
In addition to this ice aid, of course there are also ice explosions
このアイスエイドの他に、もちろんアイスエクスプロージョンもあります
bigger stuff
もっと大きなもの
This thing is more dangerous
こっちの方が危険だよ
When the ice burst is relatively small
氷の破裂が比較的小さい場合
We have this called a soft burst
これをソフトバーストと呼びます
called Blobber
ブロバーと呼ばれる
Soft bursts usually occur in very specific shapes
ソフトバーストは通常​​、非常に特殊な形で発生します
A bit like our Lianwu
私たちのLianwuに少し似ています
But it's very small
でもとても小さいです
Little Lianwu
リトル・リアンウー
The ice bursts are of course big and small
氷のはじけ方はもちろん大きいのも小さいのもある
This is 2006
これは2006年です
Some ice blasts in front of my back yard
裏庭の前で氷が吹いた
so if you don't know
それで知らないなら
what kind of steamed stuffed bun is there
どんな肉まんがあるの？
pearl balls or something
真珠玉か何か
no
いいえ
This is an ice blast
これはアイスブラストです
That time the parcel company lost money
その時、宅配会社は赤字になった
Lost us 20,000 yuan
2万元を失った
fix the roof
屋根を直す
Because the ice burst
氷が割れたので
Is the roof not pierced?
屋根に穴が開いていませんか？
But there are a lot of cold spots
でも寒いところもたくさんある
So that time it seemed like this
で、その時はこんな感じでした
The parcel company over there lost money
あそこの宅配会社は赤字になった
throughout the region
地域全体で
the one in the area
その地域にあるもの
The parcel company will pay for it
宅配会社が負担してくれるよ
This is the largest ice storm in the world record in 2010, 0.88 kilograms and 20 centimeters in diameter
これは2010年の世界記録の中で最大の氷嵐で、その大きさは0.88キロ、直径20センチです。
It's better not to go out in this weather
この天気では外出しないほうがいいです
So the clouds represent the possibility of a large ice storm.
したがって、雲は大規模な氷嵐の可能性を表しています。
Under what circumstances will an ice storm occur?
氷嵐はどのような状況で発生しますか?
This is all based on such a big
これはすべて、このような大きなことに基づいています
What conditions do you need to generate such a large ice storm?
このような大規模な氷嵐が発生するにはどのような条件が必要なのでしょうか?
Must have that ascender has very strong
アセンダーは非常に強力である必要があります
Because if the ascender is not strong enough
アッセンダーが十分に強くないと、
That thing condensed a little bit and fell off.
それが少し凝縮して落ちました。
So it has to be so strong that it goes all the way up
だからそれはずっと上まで上がるほど強くなければなりません
Then collide with others, grow bigger and longer
そして、他のものと衝突し、大きく、長く成長します
up to or even higher than that too high for an ice storm
氷嵐には高すぎる、あるいはそれ以上
The typhoon is even faster
台風はさらに早いですね
when it goes up all the way up to
まで上がったとき
About 60 to 70 meters per second
秒速約60～70メートル
so fast ascent
とても速い登り
to produce such a large ice storm
これほど大きな氷嵐を引き起こすには
Then once your ascending current is not enough to support it
そして上昇流がそれを支えるのに十分でなくなったら
it just started to fall
ちょうど落ち始めたばかりです
So when you see such a big ice storm
だから、こんな大きな氷嵐を見たら
This represents the original
これはオリジナルを表します
the speed is very very high
スピードはとてもとても速いです
So a whole bunch of this process
この一連のプロセスは
how do we study it
どうやって勉強しますか
Of course, the most direct way is to
もちろん、最も直接的な方法は、
Will go to the operator to observe
オペレーターのところに行って観察します
But I will go to the operator to observe it.
しかし、私はそれを観察するためにオペレーターに行きます。
The first consumption will be very large
最初の消費量は非常に多くなります
The second is very dangerous
2番目は非常に危険です
Generally speaking
一般的に言えば
real worst area
本当に最悪のエリア
Most likely, they just dare not go in.
おそらく普段はあえて入らないだけでしょう
dare not drive in
あえて車で乗り入れないでください
Some people go in by accident
偶然入ってしまう人もいる
If you accidentally go in, it's a serious situation.
誤って入ってしまったら大変なことになります。
lots of fighting chances to go in
戦うチャンスはたくさんある
will be beaten by ice
氷に殴られるだろう
There's something wrong with the windows too
窓にも何か問題があります
The shape of the wings has also changed
羽の形も変わってます
a lot of boil
たくさん沸騰する
We generally have another method theory
通常、別の方法理論があります
all the physical processes we know
私たちが知っているすべての物理的プロセス
represented by mathematical formulas
数式で表される
This is called a mathematical formula
これを数式といいます
The obtained partial text is represented by replacing it with
結果の部分テキストは、次のように置き換えることによって表されます。
Then formulate its initial boundary conditions
次に、その初期境界条件を定式化します
Use a computer to find a set of solutions
コンピューターを使用して一連の解決策を見つける
Then answer these
それではこれらに答えてください
Draw it with the method of computer drawing
コンピューター描画の手法で描きます
I can come and explain what the process is like
プロセスがどのようなものかを説明しに来ます
If compared with the actual observation
実際の観察と比較すると
if it's good
良かったら
We can take this cloud model
このクラウドモデルを採用できます
The help produced is a research tool
作成されたヘルプは研究ツールです
can come to study
勉強しに来ることができます
The formation of a cloud is roughly like its internal structure
雲の形成はその内部構造とほぼ同じです
So this is one of our institutes
これは私たちの研究所の一つです
Made a cloud model like this
こんな感じのクラウドモデルを作りました
make a cloud make a base cloud
クラウドを作る ベースクラウドを作る
Its pattern basically at least looks like
そのパターンは基本的に少なくとも次のようになります
Kiyun starts from the ground
キユンは地面からスタート
grow to protrude a little
少しはみ出すように成長する
And then as soon as you get to this really long, real inflammation
そして、この本当に長く続く本物の炎症に至るとすぐに、
in this flat city
この平らな街で
Produced at the top of this convective city
この対流都市の頂上で生み出される
So this is an example of a fish pattern
これは魚のパターンの例です
you can see this
これを見ることができます
Indeed compared with the real observation
実際の観察と比較すると確かに
It is indeed full of images
実にイメージが詰まっています
So this once this after
それで、これはこの後もう一度
We can put all kinds of different fish inside the fish
魚の中にいろんな種類の魚を入れることができます
ice burst cloud low ice crystals
氷の破裂雲低い氷の結晶
Draw different windcloths
さまざまな風布を描きます
and then animate it too
それからそれもアニメーション化します
You can know where the ice burst and where
どこで氷が割れたのかがわかる
It can be predicted that
ということが予測できる
The blue above is all ice
上の青はすべて氷です
The red part, the ice burst part
赤い部分、アイスバースト部分
The green part represents the part where it rains
緑色の部分は雨が降っている部分を表します
at this time
現時点では
We use it as a research tool
研究ツールとして使用します
It's still very useful
今でもとても役に立ちます
And if you want that kind of thing, you can study it.
そして、そのようなことがしたいなら、勉強すればいいのです。
how big is the flood
洪水の大きさはどれくらいですか
How much rain can you have with one fortune
一財産でどれくらいの雨が降ることができるか
Do you want to guess
推測してみますか
How much rain can an ordinary lucky flower bring
普通の幸運の花はどれくらいの雨をもたらすことができますか
How many tons can be dropped
何トン投下できるか
do you want to guess
推測したいですか
10,000 tons seems to be asking for a price
1万トンは値段を求めているようだ
100,000 tons, 1,000,000 tons
10万トン、100万トン
almost one million tons
約100万トン
even millions of tons
何百万トンでも
a simple luck
単純な幸運
so much water can come out
とてもたくさんの水が出てくる可能性があります
Anyway very very strong
とにかくとても強い
Speaking of the flood means
洪水と言えば、
I just talked about a multiple choice question
先ほど多肢選択問題についてお話しました
Everyone, be brave and choose
みなさん、勇気を出して選んでください
Which flood was the largest ever to occur on earth
地球上でこれまでに起きた最大規模の洪水はどれですか
One is the time when Datong water was in the age of shaking
一つは大同水が大地を揺るがす時代だった
The second is Deep Gold as mentioned above
2つ目は前述の通りディープゴールドです
Noah's Ark
ノアの方舟
The so-called Great Ark of Animal Rescue conveys
いわゆる動物救出の大箱舟は、
That time, it might have been Typhoon Morakot.
あの時は台風モラコットだったかも知れません。
i bring soda with this
これにソーダを持っていきます
you probably don't know
あなたはおそらく知らないでしょう
Your older self remembers having this big bottle of soda in this
昔のあなたは、この大きなボトルのソーダをこの中に入れていたことを覚えています
The fifth answer is to fly above the knot
5番目の答えは結び目の上を飛ぶことです
we have some experts here
ここには何人かの専門家がいます
The real biggest flood is not long after the formation of the ninth hill
本当の最大の洪水は、第 9 丘の形成後すぐに起こります。
That time was really the biggest
あの時が本当に一番大きかった
because why
なぜならなぜ
Now the flood is once
今、洪水は一度だけ
For example, if you are given tens of millions of tons of water
たとえば、何千万トンもの水を与えられたとします。
but what was that time
でもあの時は何だったんだろう
That rain caused the entire ocean
その雨は海全体を引き起こした
You don't have that much water now
今はそんなに水がありません
Not so much water now
今はそれほど水は多くない
Because when our earth first started
なぜなら、私たちの地球が最初に始まったとき、
There was no water for a while
しばらく水が出なかった
Later, a lot of water vapor is slowly released from the earth's crust.
その後、地殻から大量の水蒸気がゆっくりと放出されます。
Then it starts to create a lot of geo
その後、大量のジオメトリが作成され始めます
So it's not the same as silver now
だから今はシルバーと同じではない
Silver must have been dazzling back then
あの頃は銀が眩しかったんだろうな
full of dark clouds
暗雲がいっぱい
water vapor everywhere
どこにでもある水蒸気
hot everywhere
どこも暑い
volcanoes everywhere
どこにでもある火山
that steam comes out
蒸気が出てくるのは
not ordinary so-called silver
普通のいわゆるシルバーではありません
that was a volcanic eruption
それは火山の噴火でした
volcanic eruptions
火山噴火
Even in the current volcanic eruption
今回の火山噴火でも
largest part
最大部分
The released gas is still water vapor
放出されたガスは依然として水蒸気です
mostly water vapor
ほとんどが水蒸気
Second is carbon dioxide
2番目は二酸化炭素です
sulfur dioxide
二酸化硫黄
and then finally
そして最後に
it's bomb now
今は爆弾だ
So I was still an old demon at the time.
だから当時の私はまだ老悪魔だった
The most common gas is this
最も豊富なガスは実際にはこれです
For a while, the earth actually had many of these
しばらくの間、地球には実際にこれらのものがたくさんありました
But because of the environment of the earth
でも地球環境のせいで
a little cold
少し寒い
So the water will become clean soon
そうすれば水はすぐにきれいになります
So this kind of process has been going through I don't know how long
このプロセスはどれくらいの期間かわかりませんが行われています
Finally, all the excess water and air in it are all in the early morning water.
最後に、余分な水分と空気はすべて早朝の水の中にあります。
really biggest biggest flood
本当に最大の最大の洪水
This is how the world's oceans are now created
世界の海はこうして作られている
this is what is called
これがいわゆる
The biggest flood ever happened, so you guessed it
史上最大の洪水が起こった、それはご想像のとおりでした
Of course he doesn't know that he can't guess
もちろん彼は自分が推測できないことを知りません
Ok, what impact does the cloud have on the overall environment?
クラウドは環境全体にどのような影響を与えますか?
I'm not saying that the cloud is only good-looking over there.
あそこの雲だけが格好良いと言っているわけではありません。
There must be some effect on the entire atmospheric environment
大気環境全体に何らかの影響があるに違いない
What is his role like?
彼の役割はどのようなものですか？
The first everyone knows this so-called
まず誰もがこれを知っています、いわゆる
A star fish is not a fish, it nourishes all things
スターフィッシュは魚ではない、万物に栄養を与える
this
これ
The squid place is of course on the ground
イカ場はもちろん地上にあります
crops are fine
作物は大丈夫です
no if not
そうでない場合はいいえ
this is that
これはそれです
NASA this Modus
NASAのこのやり方
made this surface color
この表面の色を作りました
real color
本当の色
Overview of
の概要
you can tell by saying
言うことでわかります
some places
いくつかの場所
high humidity
高湿度
looks green
緑に見える
The surface has some straight backs
表面はまっすぐな裏面を持っています
where the color looks dry and cool of course
もちろんカラーがドライでクールに見える場合
It's just sprinkled in the desert
それは砂漠に散らばっているだけです
Like a salad in the west of China
中国西部のサラダのようなもの
and central australia
そしてオーストラリア中部
It's all desert
全部砂漠だよ
So this role needs to be adjusted
したがって、この役割を調整する必要があります
What is the second fish for?
2番目の魚は何ですか？
Is the most efficient cleaner of the atmosphere
最も効果的な大気浄化剤です
inside our atmosphere
私たちの大気圏の中で
If there is no such process of rain
このような雨のプロセスがなければ
Our pollution has been accumulating and accumulating
私たちの汚染は蓄積され続けています
just stop
ただやめて
it won't be cleared
それはクリアされないでしょう
that clearing effect
その浄化効果
The strongest effect is this rain
一番強い効果はこの雨だ
This is the mechanism of heavy rain and rain
これが大雨や大雨のメカニズムです
The mechanism of Shen Yuyu is the biggest
沈玉宇の仕組みが最大
the most efficient
最も効率的な
It is the so-called sinking rain effect
いわゆる沈み込み雨効果です
Didn't we just talk about Ling Jiehe?
さっき林潔和の話をしませんでしたか？
You only need a Lingjiehe
必要なのはLingjieheだけです
It is possible to absorb this moisture
この水分を吸収することが可能です
Then a cloud or raindrop is formed
その後、雲や雨粒が形成されます
As long as you are in the rainy process
あなたが雨の過程にいる限り
Then your thing and the river
それからあなたのものと川
Even in this rain everything falls to the ground
この雨でもすべてが地面に落ちる
so the air is clean
だから空気がきれいです
so why after it rains
ではなぜ雨が降った後なのか
The air seems to be cleaner
空気がきれいになったような気がします
Or the air looks cleaner after it snows
あるいは雪が降った後は空気がきれいに見える
It is because of this process of rain
雨が降る過程のせいです
Sweep away these polluting things in the air
空気中にあるこれらの汚染物を一掃してください
This is an experiment done by others
これは他人がやった実験です
The representative said that after it snows
代表者は雪が降った後はこう言った。
Indeed, I saw a circle around the snow
確かに雪の周りに輪が見えた
This sweat, this dirt
この汗、この汚れ
was brought down by this snow
この雪で倒れた
it means
その意味は
it does have a good cleaning effect
この浄化効果は非常に優れています
There is another very expensive thing over here
ここにはもう一つ非常に高価なものがあります
This thing is called Gridfield Gap
これはグリッドフィールドギャップと呼ばれるものです
snow or rain
雪または雨
When the particle is very small
粒子が非常に小さい場合
it clears well
よく晴れる
It clears well when the particles are large
粒子が大きいとよく切れる
But when the particle is between 0.1 and 1 as the surface
ただし、粒子が表面として 0.1 から 1 の間にある場合、
It can hardly be cleared, and it can be cleared very little
ほとんどクリアできない、ごくわずかしかクリアできない
So there's always these 0.1 to 1 millimeters in the air
つまり、空気中には常にこの 0.1 ～ 1 ミリメートルが存在します。
A thing of this great concentration
これほどの濃度のもの
That thing is almost impossible to clear
それをクリアするのはほぼ不可能です
That seems like how you wash it those particles
それは粒子を洗う方法のようです
always in the air
常に空中に
there's a physical reason for that
それには物理的な理由がある
we used to do
私たちがやっていた
A calculation model we made
私たちが作った計算モデル
calculated result
計算結果
That's exactly what it looks like
まさにその通りです
The middle one is called Griffel Gammel
真ん中のものはグリフェル・ガンメルと呼ばれます
This guy Griffel when he first brought it up
グリッフェルという男が最初にそれを持ち出したとき
there is such a possibility
そのような可能性があります
Then we have confirmed that this phenomenon does exist.
そして、この現象が実際に存在することを確認しました。
ok
Ok
So this third character is
したがって、この 3 番目の文字は、
Clouds affect the Earth's ambient light
雲は地球の周囲光に影響を与えます
The so-called ambient light ratio is Albido
いわゆる周囲光比はアルビドです
that of course means
それはもちろん意味します
If you look at something in space
宇宙にあるものを見たら
how bright
どれだけ明るいか
In fact, if that thing doesn't light up by itself
実際、それが自動的に点灯しない場合は、
It's the kind that inverts the color of other light sources
他の光源の色を反転させるタイプです
That brightness is the so-called slowing force
その明るさはいわゆる減速力
So the greater the retardation
したがって遅滞が大きいほど
Indicates that those things may be brighter
それらのものがより明るくなる可能性があることを示します
In terms of the celestial body
天体でいえば
inside our celestial body
私たちの天体の内部
The brightest in the sky are of course the sun and the moon
空で一番明るいのはもちろん太陽と月です
The two largest
最大の2つ
Of course the sun brightens itself
もちろん太陽は自らを輝かせます
Of course the moon is illuminated by the sun
もちろん月は太陽に照らされて
besides these two
この二人のほかに
Which is the brightest celestial body
最も明るい天体はどれですか
Venus
金星
Has anyone voted for Mars?
火星に投票した人はいますか？
No
いいえ
strangeness
奇妙さ
all Venus fans
ヴィーナスファンの皆様
But it is true
しかし、それはあります
Venus is nothing but the sun and the moon
金星は太陽と月にほかならない
third
三番目
third two
3番目の2
is auric
オーラです
why is venus so bright
なぜ金星はあんなに明るいのか
these two reasons
この2つの理由
because it's close
近いから
first because it's close
まずは近いから
it's closer to us
それは私たちの近くにあります
so this is the first reason
これが最初の理由です
The first reason is because it is surrounded by a very dense cloud
一つ目の理由は、非常に濃い雲に囲まれているためです。
What about his clouds, unlike our place where there are no clouds?
雲のない私たちの場所とは違って、彼の雲はどうでしょうか？
He surrounded all the ninety or so secret clouds
彼はこれら90ほどの秘密の雲をすべて取り囲んだ
But his cloud is a bad cloud
しかし彼の雲は悪い雲だ
His clouds are all acid, all are clouds of acid
彼の雲はすべて酸性で、すべてが酸性の雲です
So this is bad because Jingxing is called Vinus on the Western side
Jingxing は西側では Vinus と呼ばれているので、これは悪いです。
Weiner is a very cute girl
ウインナーはとても可愛い女の子です
But in fact, Jingxing is a very bad place
しかし実際には、京興は非常に悪い場所です
His clouds are all acid, all clouds of acid
彼の雲はすべて酸性、すべて酸性の雲
His ground is more than 400 degrees
彼の地面は400度を超えています
That's terrible. He's just hot medicine.
それはひどい。彼はただの熱い薬です。
As soon as all the water gets there, it doesn’t just boil, it literally melts away.
すべての水がそこに到達するとすぐに、沸騰するだけでなく、文字通り溶けて消えます。
His pressure is more than ninety times that of the earth's surface
彼の圧力は地表の90倍以上です
So if you're not protected, you can't breathe at all.
したがって、保護されていない場合は、まったく呼吸できなくなります。
It's as if you are shallow in this sea, about 2,000 meters under pressure
まるで水深約2000メートルの圧力のかかった海の浅瀬にいるようだ
So much pressure, this is Jingxing's surface
すごいプレッシャー、これがJingxingの表面です
Bi Xing looks so bright, but there is nothing to envy
Bi Xing はとても明るく見えますが、羨ましいことは何もありません
That's because it was blown out whole by a secret cloud
それは秘密の雲に丸ごと吹き飛ばされたからだ
So it reflects this sunlight very, very strongly
だからこの太陽光をとてもとても強く反射するのです
It looks very bright in the night sky
夜空に映えますね
Earth is not so much
地球はそれほどでもない
Earth's albedo is not as strong
地球のアルベドはそこまで強くない
So the blue part of the earth basically sees the sea surface
つまり、地球の青い部分には基本的に海面が見えます
The surface of the sea is very dark if you look directly at it.
海面を直接見るととても暗いです。
What is the reason for the reflection of the earth?
地球が反射する理由は何ですか？
Mostly because the cloud doesn't matter
主にクラウドは関係ないからです
cloud it is very white
雲はとても白いです
So when the sun shines on it, it reflects back
だから太陽が当たると反射してしまうんです
The Earth includes clouds including floor albedo
地球にはフロアアルベドを含む雲が含まれています
The reflection band is about 30%
反射帯域は約30%
So the albedo is 0.3%
つまりアルベドは0.3%です
This is our common sense of the earth's albedo
これが私たちの地球のアルベドの常識です
If cloud cover on Earth increases
地球上の雲量が増えると
The albedo of the earth will increase
地球のアルベドは上昇する
Because there are more clouds
雲が多くなったので
When there are more clouds, its albedo will increase
雲が増えるとアルベドが大きくなります
if you were an alien
もしあなたが宇宙人だったら
Because the earth is a little suddenly bright
地球が少しだけ急に明るくなったから
The biggest possible reason is that the earth's clouds suddenly increased
考えられる最大の原因は地球上の雲が突然増えたこと
then say your next question
それから次の質問を言ってください
Why do Earth's clouds increase?
なぜ地球の雲は増えるのでしょうか?
he started researching
彼は研究を始めた
There are of course various reasons for this
もちろんこれには様々な理由がありますが、
next one
次の
What is the most important greenhouse atmosphere on Earth
地球上で最も重要な温室の大気は何ですか
If you don't know a little bit, it will change
少しでも知らないと変わってしまう
right
右
The most important thing is actually water vapor
一番大切なのは実は水蒸気
Water vapor is the largest greenhouse atmosphere on Earth
水蒸気は地球上で最大の温室大気です
The so-called Hu-color equilibrium temperature on the earth is about minus 21 degrees
地球上のいわゆるHu色の平衡温度は約マイナス21度です
very cold
とても寒い
The earth is supposed to be cold
地球は寒いはずだ
But the earth is not that cold
でも地球はそこまで寒くない
Why
なぜ
Because the earth's surface releases some water vapor
地球の表面は水蒸気を放出しているため、
This water vapor surrounds our planet
この水蒸気は私たちの地球を取り囲んでいます
making the earth's surface
地球の表面を作る
So increasing the temperature
それで温度を上げると
The average temperature of our earth is about 15 degrees
私たちの地球の平均気温は約15度です
So from minus 21 degrees to 15 degrees
つまりマイナス21度から15度まで
Added 36 degrees
36度を追加
80 to 90 credits for this concentration
この集中では 80 ～ 90 クレジット
It's all crystal
全部クリスタルだよ
not carbon dioxide
二酸化炭素ではありません
Then you must feel very strange
そうしたらあなたはとても奇妙に感じるはずです
Otherwise, now everyone is teaching carbon dioxide what is the truth
そうでなければ、今では誰もが二酸化炭素の真実を教えています
Because everyone thinks that crystal aura is a state of balance
クリスタルオーラはバランスの取れた状態だと誰もが思っているから
When there is more crystal gas, it will become a cloud
結晶ガスが増えると雲になります
So go back to the state of crystal air
だから、クリスタルエアの状態に戻りましょう
it just keeps looping
それはただループし続けるだけです
So has the crystal energy increased?
それで、クリスタルのエネルギーは増加しましたか？
we do not know
我々は知りません
Let's say it's balanced
バランスが取れていると言えましょう
But the carbon dioxide cools down
でも二酸化炭素は冷える
just keep going up
ただ上がり続けてください
so it's obvious
それは明らかです
It must have this warming effect
これにはきっと温暖化効果があるはずだ
That's why we now put carbon dioxide
だからこそ今は二酸化炭素を導入しているのです
Considered an important greenhouse base
重要な温室拠点と考えられている
But if you talk about the real magnitude
しかし、本当の大きさについて言えば、
Carbon dioxide is not
二酸化炭素はそうではありません
really the biggest thing
本当に最大のこと
crystal air
クリスタルエア
In addition to water vapor, clouds actually have a great stabilizing effect
水蒸気に加えて、雲には実際に大きな安定化効果があります
It's just that clouds are difficult to measure, which is a bit of a headache
ただ、雲は測定するのが難しいので、少し頭の痛い問題です
OK, so this cloud has a lot of problems
さて、このクラウドには多くの問題があります
Are clouds stabilizing or cooling?
雲は安定しつつあるのか、それとも冷却しているのか?
Clouds, as we just talked about, are major contributors to the Earth's albedo
先ほど話したように、雲は地球のアルベドに大きく寄与しています。
So if it's cloudy, it reflects the light back
曇っていれば光が反射して戻ってきます
light is reflected much more of course
もちろん光はより多く反射されます
This means that less energy from the sun passes through
これは、太陽からのエネルギーが減少することを意味します
So in terms of its role, it should cool the ground
役割としては、地面を冷やすことです。
But if the ground radiation goes up,
しかし、地上放射線量が上昇すると、
The cloud will absorb him and then reflect it back to him
雲は彼を吸収し、彼に反射して返すでしょう
So in terms of that role, it also has a stabilizing effect
その役割という意味では、安定させる効果もあります
so this is bad, what to do
だからこれはダメだ、どうしよう
To make matters worse, low clouds are not the same as high clouds
さらに悪いことに、低い雲は高い雲と同じではありません
low cloud, it is now common opinion to say
雲が低い、と言うのが今では一般的な意見です。
low cloud it is mostly
低い雲がほとんどです
Has a warming and cooling effect
温めたり冷やしたりする効果がある
Its main function is to slow down the sunlight
その主な機能は太陽光を遅くすることです
It does not have much heat dissipation in this brook
小川からの熱を放散するのがあまり得意ではありません
no effect
無効
But high clouds like cirrus clouds
でも高い雲は巻雲のような
Just saw those cirrus clouds
ちょうどその巻雲を見ました
It does have the effect of steaming and warming
蒸して温める効果もある
If there are many cirrus clouds
巻雲が多い場合
it may creek a lot hotter
もっと暑くなるかもしれない
before spreading it back
広げる前に
it dissipates heat by itself
それ自体で熱を放散します
But its heat dissipation is the so-called black body radiation
しかし、その熱放散はいわゆる黒体放射です。
It radiates from a black body because its temperature itself is very cold
温度自体が非常に低いため、黒体から放射されます。
So it dissipates very little heat
そのため、熱の放散がほとんどありません
So it's generally
したがって、一般的には
It has more effect of steaming and warming
蒸して温める効果がさらに高まります
So now it becomes two to balance
それで今はバランスをとるために2つになります
After all, the cooling effect of low clouds is more important
結局のところ、低い雲の冷却効果の方が重要です
Is it more important for the steaming and warming effect of high clouds?
上空の雲による蒸気と温暖化の効果の方が重要なのでしょうか？
Let's see which one is more
じゃあどっちが多いか見てみましょう
right
右
low cloud or high cloud
低い雲または高い雲
Now the question is how cool is Gao Yun
さて問題は、ガオ・ユンがどれほどクールかということです
This is a big problem
これは大きな問題です
Except for the so-called cirrus clouds that you can see with your eyes
目で見えるいわゆる巻雲を除く
beyond the high altitude cirrus clouds
高高度の巻雲を越えて
It's so hot that there are cirrus clouds that are invisible to the eyes
とても暑いので目には見えない巻雲が発生しています
Its eyes can't see the silver roll, not only can't see
その目には銀のロールが見えないだけでなく、
And it's very thick
そしてとても厚いです
Its thickness is sometimes as thick as six or seven kilometers
その厚さは時には6〜7キロメートルにもなる
It's full of ice crystals
氷の結晶がいっぱいです
But because of it, the ice crystal will grow smaller
でもそのせいで氷の結晶は小さくなってしまう
you can't see your eyes can't see
君には見えない、君の目は見えない
So I thought it was not
だからそんなことないと思ってた
I can’t see it anymore, no, yes
もう見えない、いえ、はい
So now the question is
さて、質問は次のとおりです
Is that thing real or general?
それは本当ですか、それとも一般的なものですか？
Now everyone will become confused
もうみんな混乱するよ
So now NASA has another very important
さて、NASA にはもう 1 つの非常に重要な計画があります。
This mission on climate is
気候に関するこのミッションは、
to observe these things
これらのことを観察すること
Show me every layer of these clouds
この雲のすべての層を見せてください
Then observe clearly
それからはっきりと観察してください
Only when you can truly cleanse people
本当に人を清めることができてこそ
What is the role of clouds in the atmospheric environment
大気環境における雲の役割は何ですか
The role of real text or general text
実際のテキストまたは一般的なテキストの役割
This thing needs to do this
これはこれを行う必要があります
This kind of observation in three-dimensional space can
このような三次元空間での観察は、
that's a big problem
それは大きな問題です
Because satellite observations are roughly one layer
衛星観測はおよそ 1 層であるため、
Most of the satellites now have better ones
現在、ほとんどの衛星にはより優れた衛星が搭載されています
But that observation is still too far off
しかし、その観測はまだ遠いところにあります
Observing it from the ground is even more different
地上から見るとさらに違います
There are not many quantities that can have this kind of data
この種のデータを取得できる量は多くありません
There is no information on the sea
海に関する情報はありません
So the question of cloud to climate research
雲と気候の研究の問題
create very, very big problems
非常に大きな問題を引き起こす
So why this IPCC
では、なぜ IPCC なのか
This body of research climate across the board
全般的な研究環境
That is to say, for all radiation factors
つまり、すべての放射線要因について
Carbon dioxide warms up, other clouds have something to cool them down
二酸化炭素は暖められるが、他の雲には冷やすものが存在する
But it turned into a big thing here
しかしここで大変なことになりました
is its uncertainty
その不確実性は
because we have clouds and climates
私たちには雲と気候があるから
Just now these knots also know that there are too few
今、この結び目も、結び目が少なすぎることを知っています
Lingjie is producing clouds again
凌傑がまた雲を生み出している
If you have a lot of knots inside
内部に節が多い場合
a little cloud will increase
少し雲が増えてきます
So it does something else that we don't understand at all
つまり、私たちがまったく理解できない別のことを行うのです
So it has a lot of uncertainty
なので不確実性が非常に高いです
so much uncertainty
とても不確実性が高い
So this picture is often seen by many people
この写真は多くの人によく見られます
Why is this place often emphasized in its fourth report that
なぜこの場所が第4次報告書でしばしば強調されるのか。
We can only say that this thing can be determined to a certain extent
このことはある程度判断できるとしか言えません
Pretty sure, slightly sure, not sure or something
かなり確か、少し確か、よく分からない、または何か
Why do you use such words?
なぜそのような言葉を使うのでしょうか？
Because the cloud represents a great uncertainty
クラウドは大きな不確実性を表すため
there are worse nightmares inside
中にはもっとひどい悪夢がある
There are also clouds in Pingliu City
平流市にも雲があります
We're not right, Stratocity used to think that Stratocity was very dry
私たちは間違っています。Stratocity は Stratocity が非常にドライだと考えていました
no cloud possible
雲はありえない
But our recent observations show that Stratocity does have
しかし、私たちの最近の観察によると、Stratocity には実際に
On a storm you often see
よく見る嵐に
Sometimes clouds like chimneys are up there
時々煙突のような雲が上にあります
Someone actually saw it before
実際に見た人がいた
but don't know what it is
でもそれが何なのか分からない
Later someone saw it and published it
その後誰かがそれを見て公開した
But he still doesn't know why
しかし、彼はまだその理由を知りません
It is indeed in Stratocity
まさにストラトシティにある
because this has been
これはすでに行われているので
This really strong part
この本当に強い部分は
The top of this storm is already at the top of Stratocity
この嵐の頂点はすでにストラトシティの頂点にある
This so-called chimney-like chimney
このいわゆる煙突のような煙突
it's more on top of this cloud
もっとこの雲の上にある
So it's clearly in the bottle layer
つまり、明らかにボトル層にあります
We now know that in terms of radiation
私たちは今、放射線に関して次のことを知っています。
If water vapor in this vial layer
このバイアル層に水蒸気があれば
Its role in absorbing this infrared
この赤外線を吸収する役割
It is nearly 1000 times that in the bottle layer
ボトル層の1000倍近く
So it's very powerful
だからとても強力なんです
It is equivalent to building a very effective quilt in this thermal layer
これは、この保温層に非常に効果的なキルトを構築することに相当します。
Your long-wave radiation can't escape if you want to escape.
あなたが逃げたくても、長波放射線は逃げることはできません。
it's there covered
そこは覆われている
So if there are many of these things
したがって、これらのことがたくさんある場合は、
Then this positive temperature effect is incredible.
このプラスの温度効果は信じられないほどです。
so this thing knows what's going on
それで、これは何が起こっているかを知っています
We are now gradually understanding
今では徐々に理解が進んでいます
This is the result of our simulation
これは私たちのシミュレーションの結果です
indeed with that fishing mode
確かにその釣りモードでは
You can simulate it just like what you see in that satellite
その衛星で見ているのと同じようにシミュレーションできます
like a chimney cloud
煙突雲のように
So let's explain
それでは説明しましょう
In the process of generating a machine cloud
マシンクラウドを生成中
Due to the effect of these fluctuations
こうした変動の影響により、
You can make this water vapor or even moisture
この水蒸気や湿気さえも作ることができます
From the cloud all the way to the bottle layer
雲からボトル層までスプレー
and then later
そしてその後
it might stay there
そこに残るかもしれない
steam off
蒸気を切る
Then leave the air in the water completely at the bottom of the bottle layer
次に、ボトル層の底にある水中に空気を完全に残します。
so this time
それで今回は
Its vibration effect may be very powerful
その振動効果は非常に強力である可能性があります
so what about this
それで、これはどうですか
In the current climate model again
再び現在の気候モデルで
where little is considered
ほとんど考慮されていないところ
so here
それでここで
Now this problem is very, very much
さて、この問題は非常に深刻です
So this is what we just said
これが私たちが今言ったことです
inside the vial layer
バイアル層の内側
It may have a strong effect of this addition
この追加の影響が強いかもしれません
And the air in the water is in the bottle layer
そして水中の空気はボトルの層にあります
it has a long lifespan
それは長い寿命を持っています
it may have a lifespan of several years
数年の寿命があるかもしれない
Then once your life span is so long
そして、あなたの寿命があまりにも長くなったら、
What do you think about this climate change factor
この気候変動の要因についてどう思いますか
it can be very big
それはとても大きくなる可能性があります
So this is the climate model guy again
これがまた気候モデルの男です
need attention
注意が必要です
So why this cloud of uncertainty
では、なぜこの不確実性の雲が生じたのか
so important
ものすごく大事
This is one of the important reasons
これは重要な理由の 1 つです
So when the school encounters cloud problems in the future
したがって、将来学校がクラウドの問題に遭遇したとき、
Its suspicions can be explosive like this
その疑惑はこのように爆発する可能性があります
I can't help it. I don't understand.
仕方ない、分からない。
so angry
とても怒っている
Because the uncertainties of the cloud are too great
雲の不確実性が大きすぎるから
Except that this cloud has certain roles in the world
このクラウドが世界で一定の役割を担っていることを除いて
Will human activities have any impact on the cloud?
人間の活動はクラウドに影響を与えるのでしょうか?
there must be
がなければならない
The first one is what everyone calls an acid shadow
1つ目は、誰もがアシッドシャドウと呼ぶものです
Human industrial activities produce many such
人間の産業活動はそのような多くのことを生み出します
Sulfur dioxide Oxidized eggs
二酸化硫黄 酸化卵
Acid Shadow
アシッドシャドウ
The main source of sulfur dioxide is burning coal and thermal power
二酸化硫黄の主な発生源は石炭の燃焼と火力発電です。
This oxidized egg reacts with the cloud to produce acid elimination
この酸化した卵は雲と反応して酸を除去します。
Where does the acid-reducing oxidized egg come from?
酸を減らす酸化卵はどこから来たのですか?
All magnanimous people will have this problem
すべての寛大な人はこの問題を抱えているでしょう
This is when I was about to land from Tokyo
東京から着陸しようとしたときのことです
From the accounting network
会計サイトより
The entire vicinity of Tokyo is shrouded in the air of the nuclear installation
東京近郊全域が原子力施設の空気に包まれている
So there are a lot of oxidation products in it.
そのため、酸化生成物が多く含まれています。
All of them have this phenomenon inside
それらはすべて内部にこの現象を持っています
All metropolises as long as the weather is good
天気がよければすべての大都市
acid rain
酸性雨
Photos taken in 1908
1908年に撮影された写真
It's been 200 years since it was taken in 1908
1908年に撮影されたときは樹齢200年でした
it's still fine
まだ大丈夫です
But after another 60 years
しかしさらに60年後
unrecognizable
認識できない
I can't see anything from the face to the nose.
顔から鼻まで何も見えない。
Standard Acid Rain Effects
標準的な酸性雨の影響
The second one is that the influence of the moon is Xue Humei
2つ目は、月の影響が薛虎美であるということです。
Everyone should be very clear about this map.
誰もがこの地図についてよく理解しているはずです。
with tokyo influence
東京の影響で
During the northeast monsoon, a large pile of this kind of smoke is produced in the industrial area upstream of the industrial area
北東モンスーンの時期には、工業地帯の上流の工業地帯でこの種の煙が大量に発生します。
Then they come down here with the northeast monsoon
それから彼らは北東モンスーンとともにここにやって来ます
The whole is a long strip
全体が長い帯です
Japanese Jiye you can on the satellite map
衛星地図でわかる日本のジエ
We are called MODIS
私たちはMODISと呼ばれています
Seen from satellites that end reliability
信頼性を終える人工衛星から見る
often see this
これをよく見る
You can imagine why older
なぜ古いかは想像できるでしょう
Crash Island and our age
墜落島と私たちの時代
When we were young, when it was sunny in Taiwan
私たちが若かった頃、台湾が晴れていた頃
The blue sky is really very blue
青空は本当にとても青いです
It was really blue
本当に青かったです
Now children may think that the blue sky is also blue now
今の子供たちは青い空も青いと思うかもしれない
I tell you now the blue sky is not blue at all
今言っておきますが、青空は全然青くないです
Now the sky is blue, the sky is sunny, and the sky is gray
今、空は青く、空は晴れており、空は灰色です
not at all blue
全然青くない
Why
なぜ
too clear
明確すぎる
Because the neighbor next door generates a lot of
隣の住人が大量に発生しているため、
so there is no way
だから仕方ない
Here's a lot of human influence on this levitation example
この浮遊の例には人間の影響が大きく反映されています
look at its different colors
さまざまな色を見てください
It's the smog and the clean sea
スモッグときれいな海です
This contrast is too great
このコントラストは素晴らしすぎる
We don't even have that color here
この色もここにはありません
the color we have here
ここにある色
It's almost the picture of this kind of satellite that I often look at
よく見るのはほぼこの手の衛星の写真です
We Taiwanese nurses rarely see such a blue sea color
私たち台湾の看護師は、これほど青い海の色を見ることはめったにありません。
Must be through this more smoky color
もっとスモーキーな色を通ってるんだろうな
This is the distribution of small particles of PM2.5 around the world
これは世界中のPM2.5の小さな粒子の分布です
There is a lot of this kind of fine dust in the desert
砂漠にはこのような細かい塵がたくさんあります
because it's a desert
砂漠だから
But eastern China is clearly not a desert
しかし中国東部は明らかに砂漠ではない
But you can also see
しかし、あなたも見ることができます
industrial impact
工業的影響
This is almost now the highest region in the world
ここはほぼ現在世界で最も高い地域です
most concentrated area
最も集中しているエリア
So the northeast monsoon comes down
それで北東モンスーンが降ります
Taiwan is sure to enjoy
台湾もきっと楽しめるはず
OK is the Xionghu Weili team
OK 人為雄湖維力隊
already said
すでに言った
The first increases the number of condensation nuclei
1 つ目は凝縮核の数を増加させます。
If the concentration of water aeration is the same
水曝気濃度が同じ場合
The size of cloud water droplets will become smaller
雲の水滴のサイズが小さくなります
Cloud particles get smaller
雲の粒子が小さくなる
it will become more stable
より安定するでしょう
If the cloud strength is stable, it will be less likely to rain
雲の強さが安定していれば雨は降りにくい
once it doesn't rain
雨が降らなければ
It is less likely to wash away the paint dust
塗装粉が洗い流されにくい
So the possibility of air pollution
ということは大気汚染の可能性も
higher and higher
ますます高くなります
Then what
じゃあ何
Because condensation nuclei may dissolve in the water
凝結核が水に溶ける可能性があるため
condensation nuclei
縮合核
it may be relatively strong water droplets
比較的強い水滴かもしれません
easier to spill
比較容易溢滴
then we know that means
そうすればそれが意味することがわかります
a highly concentrated droplet
高濃度の液滴
it is less accretive
増加性は低いです
dirty water
汚い水
You see usually it's not very accretive
通常はあまり発生しないことがわかります
Clean water is easy to multiply
きれいな水は増殖しやすい
dirty water on the ground
地面の汚れた水
Things on the ground last longer
地面にあるものは長持ちする
the same in the cloud
クラウドでも同じ
As long as the cloud is dirty
雲が汚れている限り
That cloud will last a little longer
あの雲はもう少し続くだろう
There are usually more clouds, which increase the albedo
通常は雲が多くなり、アルベドが増加します
it lowers the surface temperature
表面温度を下げます
seriously pollute the air
深刻に空気を汚染する
OK but there's a lot more in it
わかりましたが、他にもたくさんあります
We have no mention of electrical effects
電気的影響については言及されていません
because time is not enough
時間が足りないから
so many things
とてもたくさんのこと
your best bet is
あなたの最善の策は
if you have a way to fly to the sky
空へ飛ぶ方法があるなら
Then look from below
じゃあ下から見てみる
Now of course we can't fly
今はもちろん飛べない
But someone flew for us
でも誰かが私たちのために飛んできた
This is called the International Space Station
これは国際宇宙ステーションと呼ばれています
So this one might take that voice and put it
だからこれはその声を拾ってそれを載せるかもしれない
Push to
プッシュ先
look down
見下ろす
pile of lightning
稲妻の山
OK, thank you all for today
はい、皆さん今日はありがとうございました
Thank you Jin Tai for the speech this last game last this
ジンタイ、前回の試合でスピーチしてくれてありがとう
Very good at shooting outer space to see the earth
地球を見るために宇宙を撮影するのがとても上手です
ok we have 10 minutes to start
はい、開始まで 10 分あります
do we have any questions please
何か質問はありますか
consult
相談する
ask the professor
教授に聞く
Just now the professor mentioned many kinds of
先ほど先生はいろいろな種類のことをおっしゃいましたが、
For example, Jiyin, Jianying, and Chen Jiyin
たとえば、Jiyin、Jianying、Chen Jiyin などです。
Please teach me the number sound of tornado
竜巻の数字の音を教えてください
what type of sound thanks
どのような音ですか、ありがとう
he has nothing to do with either
彼はどちらとも何の関係もありません
He said something completely different
彼は全く違うことを言いました
You are sounding like the fluctuating sound I mentioned just now
さっき言った揺らぎの音みたいだね
Also not included in the earliest mentioned
また、最初に言及されたものには含まれていません
He is another way of classifying
彼は別の分類方法です
So Long Jianfeng, rolled up, is that a cloud?
それで、Long Jianfeng、丸まって、それは雲ですか？
that's cloud
それは雲です
that cloud
あの雲
That cloud is not a cloud
あの雲は雲じゃない
Clouds are just about light
雲はほんの軽いものです
So the one that was rolled up by the wind of dragon inspection
ドラゴン検査の風に巻き上げられたもの
That name is Lu Douyun
その名は陸斗雲
Lu Douyun
ルー・ドゥユン
He looks like Ludo
彼はルドに似ている
Gradually
徐々に
Thanks
ありがとう
good
良い
Director Wang
王主任
Excuse me
すみません
That is, the continental climate will obviously
つまり、大陸性気候は明らかに
It is the polluted road that will obviously pollute Taiwan
台湾を明らかに汚染するのは汚染された道路です
That's our main polluting line
それが私たちの主な汚染源です
That is to say, the northeast monsoon
つまり北東モンスーン
The Northeast is not a continent
北東部は大陸ではありません
The Northeast comes from Japan and the Pacific Ocean.
北東部は日本と太平洋から来ています。
So why the mainland
ではなぜ本土なのか
going in such a strange direction
とても奇妙な方向に進んでいます
blow to Taiwan
台湾への打撃
The northeast monsoon is only because
北東モンスーンの理由は、
to us is northeast
私たちにとって北東です
But from the original place, I don’t think it’s the Northeast
でも本来の場所からすると東北ではないと思うんです
that domineering transfer
その横暴な移籍
In fact, it is mostly a circular motion.
実際、それはほとんど円運動です。
a little more
もう少し
it won't say from there
そこからは言わない
It's all the way from the northeast
ずっと北東からです
not like this
こんなんじゃない
so this situation
それでこの状況
It's like bypassing Japan and coming back.
日本を経由して戻ってくる感じです。
Bypass Japan, South Korea and come again
日本、韓国を経由してまた来てください
so keep coming
だからこれからも来てね
Another little problem is that
もう一つのちょっとした問題は、
Just mentioned that water vapor is the main greenhouse gas
先ほど、水蒸気が主な温室効果ガスであると述べました
But crocodile carbon is man-made
しかし、クロコダイルカーボンは人工的に作られたものです
a greenhouse gas that has been increasing
増加している温室効果ガス
After the crocodile carbon dioxide increases
ワニの二酸化炭素が増加した後
until the temperature increases
気温が上がるまで
Does the increase in temperature increase the stability of the earth's water vapor?
気温の上昇により、地球の水蒸気は着実に増加しますか?
After that lift up
その後リフトアップ
The temperature increased further
さらに気温が上がりました
Will it have such a vicious effect?
そんなに悪影響があるのでしょうか？
this has a possibility
これには可能性があります
not completely impossible
完全に不可能ではない
But now when reading this article
しかし、今この記事を読んでいると、
On a yearly scale
年間規模で見ると
more water vapor
より多くの水蒸気
Rainfall will also increase
雨量も増えるだろうし
because of the source of moisture
湿気の源だから
The source of that rain is water vapor
その雨の源は水蒸気です
So you make water vapor and rain increase
それで水蒸気と雨が増える
So on a yearly basis
なので年単位で見ると
Take it easy
落ち着いて
These two should balance each other
この 2 つは互いにバランスをとる必要があります
So the annual flower increase and the annual precipitation
したがって、年間の花の増加と年間降水量は
The two should just cancel out
二人は打ち消してしまえばいいのに
So for the whole year
だから一年中
That is, on average, the amount of air in water in your earth
これは、地球の水に含まれる空気の平均量です。
indeed will increase
確かに増えるだろう
But the rainfall will also increase
でも雨量も増えるだろうし
But what you just asked probably meant
でも、あなたが今尋ねたことはおそらく意味するところです
The increased air volume in the water
水中の空気の量が増えると、
Will it increase the temperature inside the earth?
地球内部の温度は上昇しますか？
the answer is yes
答えははいです
And the so-called warming
そしていわゆる温暖化
It is mentioned in the mode that this calculation is included in it.
この計算がその中に含まれていることはモードに記載されています。
I've already factored in this warming up.
このウォーミングアップはすでに織り込み済みです。
good
良い
is there any problem
何か問題ある
professor
教授
Just that video, the last video
あのビデオ、最後のビデオだけ
It's like burning the physiology
生理機能を燃やすようなものだ
what does that mean
どういう意味ですか
There are not many, but the one that seems to be on fire
数は多くないけど燃えそうなのは
you say green red
あなたは緑赤と言います
red a lot like
赤がよく似ている
The one that burns like magma
マグマのように燃えるもの
That's actually in space
それは実際に宇宙にあります
That's called Aurora
それはオーロラと呼ばれています
like the aurora borealis
オーロラのように
Are there so many auroras?
オーロラってこんなにたくさんあるの？
why is it light
なぜ軽いのか
the red one all over the place
あちこちにある赤いもの
fixed bit by bit
少しずつ修正されました
very many
非常に多くの
That is the night in the city
それは都会の夜です
of course you see a little
もちろん少し見えます
you don't really see a light
あなたには本当に光が見えない
Lights across the metropolitan area
首都圏に灯りがともる
Maybe it's in space
もしかしたら宇宙にあるかもしれない
waste time
時間を無駄にする
The whole, for example, the whole of Taipei City
全体、例えば台北市全体
just see a little
少しだけ見てください
it's a light like this
こんな感じのライトです
all covered
すべてカバーされています
are all cities
すべての都市です
Thanks
ありがとう
we just want to ask
私たちはただ聞きたいだけです
you just mentioned
あなたは今言いました
We currently lack global
現在、グローバルな人材が不足しています
3D Cloud Observation
3D雲観測
then i'm curious
それから私は興味があります
is there any possibility
可能性はありますか
can proceed
続行できます
because we usually now see
なぜなら私たちは今、普通に見ているからです
just look up from the ground
ただ地面から見上げるだけ
looking down from the sky
空から見下ろしている
just to see the flickering
ちらつきを見るためだけに
is there any possibility
可能性はありますか
Thanks
ありがとう
And the possibility is that
そして可能性があるのは、
It's better to have a lot of these tactics
この戦略はたくさん持った方が良いです
One of the current satellites is
現在の衛星の 1 つは、
a cloud radar
雲レーダー
That cloud moon called Clausian
クロージアンと呼ばれるあの雲の月
It is different from ordinary satellites
普通の衛星とは違う
Ordinary satellites are cloud satellites that use visible photosynthesis
通常の衛星は、目に見える光合成を利用する雲衛星です。
look
見て
But what you see is a plane equal to this
しかし、あなたが見ているのはこれと等しい平面です
just one layer
1層だけ
This new relatively new relic
この比較的新しい遺物
it can penetrate
それは浸透することができます
Then in theory it could see several layers
理論的には、いくつかの層が見える可能性があります
The current satellite
現在の衛星
it is not a geostationary satellite
静止衛星ではありません
If geostationary satellite
静止衛星の場合
It says it can be 24 hours a day
24時間可能だそうです
all have been watching
みんなが見ていた
At present, this kind of satellite is only a kind of orbiting satellite
現時点では、この種の衛星は周回衛星の一種にすぎません
So it just selects
だからそれはただ選択するだけです
just for a certain period of time
一定期間だけ
so the data
それでデータは
incomplete is
不完全です
but there is a possibility in the future
しかし将来的には可能性はある
If we say that the future technology is so high that
未来のテクノロジーがこんなに高度になっていると言ったら、
Pompeo also has such a thing
ポンペオにもそういう事あるよ
There is also this radar
こんなレーダーもあります
There is also this cloud radar
こんな雲レーダーもあります
From such a high altitude of tens of thousands of kilometers
何万キロもある高地から
penetrate the ground and make observations
地面に侵入して観測する
that's possible
それは可能です
This kind of global 3D observation is possible
このような全球3次元観測が可能です
Professor OK Wang
OK 王教授
thank you for a very good presentation
とても良いプレゼンテーションをありがとう
I have a question
質問があります
You mean the water and water vapor on the earth
地球上の水と水蒸気のことですね
Is it constant
一定ですか
won't it disappear into space
宇宙に消えてしまうんじゃないか
Yes
はい
if so far
これまでであれば
Disappeared because no one observed
誰も観察しないので消えてしまいます。
So since no one observed
だから誰も観察しなかったから
We assume it is always
常にそうだと仮定します
always balanced
常にバランスの取れた
so many things are said
とてもたくさんのことが言われます
Let's just say we haven't seen evidence to the contrary
反対の証拠はまだ見ていないとだけ言っておきましょう
That is to say, we don't know for sure
つまり、確かなことは分かりません
The water in the earth is increasing
地球中の水は増えている
Maybe there is a lot of water coming in from outer space, we don't know
おそらく宇宙から大量の水が入ってくるかもしれないが、私たちは知らない
So do you think there is such a possibility?
それで、そのような可能性はあると思いますか？
Of course it's possible
もちろん可能です
It's just that we have nothing to do with it
それは私たちには何の関係もないというだけです
Directly connected to the earth, there is another promise
大地と直結した、もうひとつの約束
That's what we call Jiawan
それを私たちはジアワンと呼んでいます
After oxidation, the pill will produce water
錠剤は酸化すると水が生成されます
That's really putting it together
それは本当にそれをまとめています
A lot of steamed juice is due to the oxidation of Jiawan
蒸し汁が多いのはジアワンの酸化によるものです
The generated water vapor is over there
発生した水蒸気はあそこにある
So now if the ground is like
それで今、地面がこんな感じだったら
If more and more such pills are released underground,
このような錠剤が地下にどんどん放出されれば、
after it is oxidized
酸化した後
it produces oxidized water
酸化水が生成される
likely to increase
増加する可能性が高い
It's also possible that this is another possible measure
これもまた一つの策として考えられる
ok last question
はい、最後の質問です
ask teacher wang
王先生に聞いてください
you just mentioned that there are
あなたは今、あると言いました
Tiny particles with negative subscale sizes cannot be sucked down by rainwater
負のサブスケールサイズを持つ小さな粒子は雨水によって吸い込まれることはありません
If so, will there be more and more pollutants in the air?
もしそうなら、空気中の汚染物質はますます増えるのでしょうか？
ah
ああ
it gets to a point where it might reach a certain balance
一定のバランスに達する可能性がある点に達する
not always
常にではない
take that sentence back in half
その文を半分に戻してください
If humans do not go too far
人間が行き過ぎなければ
if humans go too far
人間が行き過ぎると
Then I think it will keep increasing
その後も増えていくと思います
Because it will exceed the nature of this
この性質を超えてしまいますので
This efficiency in removing pollution from the air
空気から汚染物を除去するこの効率
Once you exceed this limit
この制限を超えると
it keeps increasing
それは増え続けています
This is the so-called wrong away
いわゆる間違ったアウェイです
just follow
ただフォローしてください
we all know why
誰もが理由を知っています
elaborate why make me hot
なぜ私を熱くさせるのか詳しく説明します
Because its soup is called wrong away
スープが評判悪いから
it can't be balanced
それはバランスが取れない
A water vapor it is the same as the earth
水蒸気は地球と同じです
Its water vapor also flowed from the ground
その水蒸気は地面からも流れ出ていました
it pops out of the ground
それは地面から飛び出す
we are tough here
私たちはここでは厳しいです
then we will take business
それなら仕事をしましょう
because it is too close to the sun
太陽に近すぎるから
it's too hot
暑すぎる
so it's been water vapor
だからそれは水蒸気だった
it broke down shortly after
それはすぐに壊れた
So its water vapor decomposes
その水蒸気が分解するので、
so it's not in its atmosphere
だからそれはその雰囲気ではない
So that elaborate atmosphere
その凝った雰囲気
That's hundreds of times the weight of the earth
それは地球の数百倍の重さです
Because its air-conditioning is not like ours running into the sea
なぜなら、そのエアコンは海に流れ込む私たちのようなものではないからです。
no , not gas
いいえ、ガスではありません
it's always been inside its origin
それは常に原点の中にあった
So this great potential
ですから、この素晴らしいポテンシャルは
There's no way it can go back, there's no way it can be balanced
元に戻ることはできないし、バランスをとることもできない
Then what I just said at this time
では、この時私が言ったことは、
If human beings are always in the air
もし人間が常に空中にいたら
send in this
これを送ってください
so many particles
非常に多くの粒子
someday
いつか
The forces of nature cannot remove
自然の力では取り除くことはできません
this time is
今回は
It is not stipulated, this is point on no return
規定されていないので返品不可です
it's possible
それが可能だ
OK, let's thank Director Wang again
OK、王監督にもう一度感謝しましょう
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました